<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log(); - conference</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/conference.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-04-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>&gt;&gt;&gt; pyconweb.talks.select_speaker('acetakwas')</title><link href="/article/goto-pyconweb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-07T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-07T13:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-07:/article/goto-pyconweb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;München, München, hier komme ich!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not big on festivities or rituals, but this year's Feb-14th day presented me 
a wonderful "opportunity", which I was quick to seize by the throat. It was an 
early early-bird tickets announcement. But more importantly, it was also a 
notification of the closing window on CFPs within the 24 hours to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I felt optimistic about a possible chance to speak, 
and quickly put together the draft for a talk proposal. To get some external review, 
I reached out to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidism"&gt;davidism&lt;/a&gt; on the 
&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/ZVcuNu"&gt;Pallets Projects' Discord server&lt;/a&gt;. A few 
minutes on and I was good to go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I submitted, informed the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yinye_m"&gt;girlfriend&lt;/a&gt;, and we kept 
our phalanges crossed. 12 days later, I got the first feedback. I should 
commend the organising PyConWeb organising team for being really nice all the 
way. I got the notification about the accepted talk in another 11 days -- March 
09, precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So come &lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/talks/26-05-2019/werkzeug-whats-in-it-for-me"&gt;26th May, 2019&lt;/a&gt;, 
I will be giving a talk on one of the nifty tools that exist in the arsenal of 
&lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/"&gt;Pallets Projects&lt;/a&gt;: the &lt;strong&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/strong&gt; library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/p/werkzeug/"&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/a&gt;, which I'd much rather refer 
to as the WSGI swiss-army knife, is one of those brilliant pieces of software 
out there that have enjoyed little attention. Permit me to blame the 
unpopularity of Werkzeug on the fame of Flask, which is what most people 
interface with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/about/"&gt;Armin Ronacher&lt;/a&gt;, who, over the years, has created 
an &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/projects/"&gt;army of useful tools&lt;/a&gt; across a spectrum of 
language ecosystems (he's a great inspiration), created Werkzeug in 2007. This was 
three years before the birth of &lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/p/flask/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;, 
which built on Werkzeug, has become the quintessential Python microframework 
for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is titled: &lt;strong&gt;Werkzeug: What's in it for me?&lt;/strong&gt; It will take the audience 
on a subliminal, revelatory journey that will unearth the most kept secrets of 
the "underweb". &lt;strong&gt;Okay, not quite. ;)&lt;/strong&gt; You can pretty much think of it as a simple 
introduction to the &lt;em&gt;good parts&lt;/em&gt; of the Werkzeug toolset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have used Flask, then you have certainly used Werkzeug. But the 
distinction must be made that, while Flask is a framework, Werkzeug is a library.
While you interact with the Flask API as a developer, Flask talks to the web 
server quite easily by leveraging the Werkzeug API. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werkzeug, on the other hand, cannot be spoken about without the mention of 
&lt;a href="https://wsgi.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;WSGI&lt;/a&gt;, which is, essentially, what it 
wraps. If you know a thing or two about the early-day struggles with web 
programming in Python and how WSGI came forth as the silver bullet that 
alleviated all of our web-server communication problems, then you would be 
quick to laud the efforts of Armin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/"&gt;PyConWeb&lt;/a&gt;, Munich is a niche PyCon event. So rather than be a 
generic &lt;a href="http://pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon event&lt;/a&gt; like many others, the organisers have 
chosen to take a rather different and interesting approach by narrowing the 
scope of the event to web technologies. I do not currently know of a more 
perfect event at which to have a talk on Werkzeug delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's an interesting coincidence that the name 
&lt;a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Werkzeug#Etymology"&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/a&gt; has its roots in 
the German language, having the meaning "work stuff".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, it's back to prepping for München, for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liebe Grüße.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="talk"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="presentation"></category><category term="werkzeug"></category><category term="pallets"></category><category term="pocoo"></category><category term="public speaking"></category><category term="armin ronacher"></category></entry></feed>