<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log(); - essay</title><link href="http://tosinmash.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tosinmash.com/feeds/essay.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tosinmash.com/</id><updated>2016-01-11T05:15:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>I am Reading Papers</title><link href="http://tosinmash.com/article/i-am-reading-papers.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-11T05:15:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-01-11T05:15:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:tosinmash.com,2016-01-11:/article/i-am-reading-papers.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my plans for 2016 is to expose myself to academic papers.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If I had a resolution for the new year, it would be my plan to read one academic paper per day. I feel as though reading people's documented research work would help broaden my knowledge and deepen my insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking for a way to crowdsource paper suggestions from a source, namely &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-recommended-list-of-essays-papers-to-read-one-per-day-in-2016-for-an-autodidact-who-wants-to-widen-his-horizon?share=1"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;. However, as I didn't get the much needed feedback in due time, &lt;a href="http://google.com/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; was my next stop. My google search led me to &lt;a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love"&gt;this page on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After launching the first paper in my document-reader software, I was surprised to see that my earlier projections of papers being under 20 pages was flawed, and so I decided to replan the whole paper-reading thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I will now attempt to read at least one paper per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this are not far fetched. I don't want to consume these publications like some fictional works. Instead, I want to read to near-full if not full understanding of their content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper I am currently reading, my first, is "Architectural Styles and the Design of Network-based Software Architectures" by &lt;strong&gt;Roy Thomas Fielding&lt;/strong&gt;. It was his submission for a doctoral program in the year 2000.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="essay"></category><category term="paper"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="dissertation"></category><category term="activity"></category></entry></feed>