<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>acetakwas.log();</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/</link><description>while True: print    &lt;strong&gt;\&lt;/strong&gt;</description><atom:link href="http://takwas.github.io/feeds/family.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 03:25:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Life-Log: January 2, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/02.01.2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of January 1, the previous night, while writing for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="/category/life-log.html"&gt;Life Log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I laid on the dinning chairs hoping to wake as soon as power was restored. For whatever reasons, it wasn't until one of my alarms went off at &lt;strong&gt;5.15AM&lt;/strong&gt; that I got up to realize that the power had long been supplied. At the time, my cousin, Deji was watching Sky Sports in the parlour area of the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On waking up I read the bible. This is something I have not been doing consistently, however, this time, I don't intend to rush through this; so I'm taking it very slow and hopefully steady. I read thirteen verses: &lt;strong&gt;Genesis 1.1-13&lt;/strong&gt;. These verses describe the &lt;strong&gt;first three days of Creation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I reminded myself of the plan to begin reading academic papers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aunt and the rest of the family, on waking up, joined us in the living room, and we said our morning prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a Saturday, it was only natural that we would do some sanitation. And so that followed. I did spend 'extra' amount of time cleaning and reassembling my small makeshift wardrobe (testament to cleaning obsessions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/JMsrD0H"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/JMsrD0Hm.jpg" title="Cabinet" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At noon, I had my meal, and went on to spend some time on IRC while doing some other regular things I would do usually do on my computer: sort files, check code and repos on &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, read code, surf the web sourcing more and more general knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was on IRC, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;empdokles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (an IRC buddy) asked if we could work together on an application messaging extension for Flask. I think it's a great idea that would also require quite a bit of a learning curve. For instance, neither of us is good with Javascript, but our intended application would definitely need it, so we'd need to learn that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I was able to fix a small bug with my blog that was caused by conflicting options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am also under pressure to contribute code to my team's projects, particularly &lt;strong&gt;project &lt;em&gt;jobnownow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the one we intend to get out as soon as possible. I am only trying to be consered calm and organized, as when activities are fully resumed, time would become a wilder horse to tame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I still have quite a lot of things lined up. Some might be done, and some I may have to let go. Among them, four projects for my team -- one is a hospital information system management application for a client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I have a Java certification examination, the OCAJP 1Z0-803 examination, which was again postponed until mid-January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I have entreprenuerial and Python meetups which I signed up for last year. I also have my eyes -- but not my mind -- on the &lt;a href="http://cchubnigeria.com/blog/"&gt;BBC Africa's ideas workshop&lt;/a&gt; scheduled for later this month at CcHub, Yaba.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also the &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/lagos/"&gt;DjangoGirls web development workshop&lt;/a&gt; coming up. Last year as well, I signed up for this as a mentor. This one won't hold until February 2016 though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Very recently, a co-developer acquaintance at NIIT informed me of Facebook's &lt;a href="https://www.internet.org/innovationchallenge"&gt;app innovation challenge&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="http://internet.org"&gt;Internet.org&lt;/a&gt; for Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asides that, I have plans to code my own IRC bot. So I'm making efforts towards that as well. At the moment, I am trying to write unit tests for an open source bot, &lt;a href="http://github.com/takwas/theb0t"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ekan0ra&lt;/em&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;batul&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;. I also started working on this last year: &lt;a href="http://github.com/takwas/sawkat"&gt;sawkat&lt;/a&gt;. I have begun learning about the &lt;a href="https://github.com/twisted/twisted"&gt;&lt;code&gt;twisted&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Python library which is used for coding IRC clients and bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a different note, I delayed my new year greetings messages until about 10PM yesterday. And that's when I unleashed them to their respective recipients. I'm sure the reponses would be flooding in by morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past 12AM, I got to reading the introductory part of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roy Fielding's&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; well known dissertation on software architecting, particulary because it is also widely recommended to anyone looking to fully comprehend and build &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer"&gt;RESTful APIs&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to this, I had no idea what the typical size of an academic dissertation was; I had projected something under 20 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my disappointment, I opened Roy's work to behold a close-to-200-page work. As a result of this, I have now rethought my paper reading plan. I will no longer try to complete one paper per day. Instead, I'll spread these papers across days and try to read them through. So help me God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] Apply for the DjangoGirls workshop - &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/lagos/apply/"&gt;https://djangogirls.org/lagos/apply/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is being discussed on the Python-Nigeria mailing list. Subscribe to this here: &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 03:25:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-03:article/02.01.2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category><category>january</category><category>church</category><category>family</category></item><item><title>Life-Log: January 1, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/01.01.2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2016 kicked off on a rather normal note. Last night, a few hours before 12AM, we (me and my aunt's family) were at the church. Church service lasted till just after new year -- about 12.20AM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got home and I broke my day-long food break (no pun intended). I had some malt (Amstel Malta) -- I didn't get one to buy at the time we left church. I would later refuse to take any of the fizzy drinks offered during lunch because of this; plus I felt my aunt might not have been pleased I took one of the malt drinks (there were four cans, and I had one of them) in the refrigerator -- and milk (Hollandia Milk, sold for 130 naira). We had prayers, and then it was the next meal round for me. I had some &lt;em&gt;garri&lt;/em&gt; and chicken, which of course, my aunt handed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, getting up at about 6AM, we kick started the day. We were to attend church is the practice at my aunt's church. I have partaken in that, the last two years. So I went on to wash the two cars -- my aunts' and her husbands'. We left the house after 9 O'Clock, and when we arrived at the church, it was already 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first-day-of-the-year program is usually geared towards the announcement of a new &lt;strong&gt;anchor&lt;/strong&gt; -- something we chant in faith, at the end of every church service, all year round. Amongst other things, the anchor's declaration is usually preceded by about three prophecies. And so it was today. The announcement came in the third: &lt;strong&gt;"O God: Thou art my HELP, and my DELIVERER"&lt;/strong&gt;; a declaration drawn out of Psalm 70 vs 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rest of the family, I left the church after 4PM, after having stayed in traffic for about an hour. We had left Folabi and Dapo -- two of my cousins -- at the church. They would much later, much to their surprise, find their way home themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I got a call from my pastor to check up on his phone, and help fix an issue. Alas, the issue was that his newly installed Skype app wasn't connecting to the internet, and was displaying an "offline" status. When, I got there, it just worked without me touching it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently helped purchase a new smartphone for my pastor's wife, and offered to help diagnose her laggy old phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were the activities that took up most of my evening, even until just before now (current system time: 21.54) that I'm writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to hack some code tonight, but there is no power supply at the moment; this battery'll only last a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my plans for 2016, I hope to read a paper a day as a way to become ever more read and deepen my insight in my autodidactic journey. I haven't read any today, but I found some &lt;a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love"&gt;very awesome resource on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am crowdsourcing for paper suggestions. You can contribute your to-read paper/essay suggestions in the comments. I also have this question on Quora: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Quora, I found &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/Obinna-Okechukwu"&gt;this really interesting profile&lt;/a&gt; on Quora minutes after returning from the new year cross-over church service. He has a &lt;a href="https://tcsnotes.quora.com/"&gt;Quora-hosted blog&lt;/a&gt;, where he reviews or puts details of Computer Science papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/James-L-Moyer?share=1"&gt;this other guy&lt;/a&gt; -- creator of &lt;a href="http://www.TheAutodidactLife.com"&gt;AutodidactLife&lt;/a&gt; -- who encouraged me to read transcripts of TED talks. His answers on Quora show that he has some insightful knowledge on autodidactism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More personally, I didn't speak with my mum today, but I did call my grandma and sister. My sister is with a cousin (Aunt Ladun) for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 07:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-01:article/01.01.2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category><category>january</category><category>first day</category><category>church</category><category>fast</category><category>family</category></item></channel></rss>