<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log(); - irc</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://takwas.github.io/feeds/irc.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://takwas.github.io/</id><updated>2016-02-03T14:10:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Ubuntu Africa Calls</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-01T05:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-03T14:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-02-01:/article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Communities drive growth. Ubuntu Africa is for all Linux and Ubuntu users in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;This post is about the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa community's&lt;/a&gt; meeting that held in their &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;IRC channel&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday the 26th of January, 2016&lt;/em&gt;. You could read the raw logs of the meeting &lt;a href="http://52.17.74.45/freenode-%23ubuntu-africa/2016-01-27-18-31-20.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but my guess is that reading logs like that might not be the most enjoyable task for your eyes. So I have tried to make this blog post a more pleasant-for-the-eyes version of it. :)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa&lt;/a&gt; is a community of Ubuntu (and Linux) users within the shores of the African continent. There are several local communities (&lt;em&gt;LoCos&lt;/em&gt;) specific to countries, but this group is limited only to the continent. It aims to bring together these LoCos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that coming together to work together will bring about a more rapid growth. Owing to our disparate skills individually, we need communities like this that will present us with people who are skilled in the areas that we are lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the &lt;a href="http://loco.ubuntu.com/teams/"&gt;directory of Ubuntu LoCos&lt;/a&gt;, I find it a little surprising that there are no efforts for an active community in my home country, Nigeria. Many people I have met scarcely even know about &lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/InternetRelayChat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; around here. More so with the coming of &lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recent foray into the African developer community had informed me about this event a few days earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes before the meeting, some users (myself inclusive) had arrived the IRC channel and engaged in discussions while patiently waiting for the scheduled meeting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting began at the set time. And it was, as it was customary, chaired by a user whom had been elected in the last meeting Naeil Zoueidi (@Na3iL)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from Tunisia. The other person who seemed to have some good footing in the house was Miles Sharp (@Kilos)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the meeting came from different African nations including Cameroon (with the highest population and mostly first-timers), Tunisia, South Africa, Ghana, Zimbabwe, RDC and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary language used during discussion was English. However, Kilos pointed out that if any user struggled with the English language, they could use their own language (most likely French) in the hope that someone would translate for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt; IRC channel has a bot called &lt;strong&gt;QA&lt;/strong&gt; that logs meetings and does a few other tasks. At the beginning of meetings attending users are expected to introduce themselves using the format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When a user does this correctly, the bot would respond to the user confirming receipt of the information. This is doable anytime during the meeting. So if a user comes in late, that's the first thing they'd be expected to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that the bot performs no parsing whatsoever on this given data and just logs it as is. Therefore, it's in a user's best interest to adhere (strictly) to the format given above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Before the meeting, there had been an &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/AfricanTeams/Meetings/20160127"&gt;agenda page&lt;/a&gt; -- I believe this was open for suggestions on the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; -- iterating the issues to be discussed at the meeting. And this was strictly followed during the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Meeting Excerpts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;The Ubuntu Africa community is currently an unofficial group. It would need more activity to gain the official recognition.&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it is important to note that all members have a mandate to try and convince users from African Linux local communities/user-groups to join the Ubuntu Africa community whilst still being active in their respective communities, as this community is country-agnostic and aims to bring us all under one umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting had a number of first-timers (myself included) in attendance. The new members were recognised. And we learnt of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/CameroonianTeam/NewMembers/en"&gt;Ubuntu local community in Cameroon&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/mailman/listinfo/ubuntu-cm"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users were encouraged to get word out about the fledgling community through their social hangouts (Facebook, Twitter and the rest...). More suggestions came in on how to  get the publicizing done. Users suggested YouTube videos, Twitter posts (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt;) and blog posts (like the one you are reading now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement was that Pieter Engelbrecht (@chesedo) from South Africa would &lt;s&gt;put up the blog post.&lt;/s&gt; create a tweet about the community using the hashtag &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;"#ubuntu-africa"&lt;/a&gt;. And just in case you want to help get the word out too, here's the link to share: http://ubuntu-africa.info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chair of the meeting raised a point about making some improvements to the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info"&gt;current website of the community&lt;/a&gt; -- adding a blog section to it. This brought our attention to the designer of the current portal, Raoul Snyman (@superfly) from South Africa and due thanks were accorded by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@superfly revealed that the current site was implemented using the static blog generator, &lt;em&gt;Nikola&lt;/em&gt;, meaning it already comes with a blogging feature, although it hadn't yet been activated, since no one had been available to blog on the site. @Na3iL offered to help with the blogging, and in the end it was agreed that the task would be handled collaboratively by @superfly (technically) and @Na3iL (literarily).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Mawutor Donkor from Ghana (@mawutor) made one final suggestion in this regard about getting involved in Ubuntu-Lab projects for schools as a way to gain some media attention.. Their suggestion was commended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to something more technical. Another memeber of the group Cameroonian member @ongolaBoy talked about the issues surrounding approval of our mirror. He stated that the status of submission had gone from "pending" to "unofficial", which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shared the URL to the Launchpad page of the mirror: https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+mirror/miroir.cm.auf.org-archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone was impressed with this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last topic tended toward "social" again, and it was kick-started by the chair with the question, "Any new coming events?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilos mentioned the upcoming release of Ubuntu 16.04, which we all anticipate for April. The Tunisian folks (@Na3iL and @elacheche_anis) got talking about some SysAdmin workshop still in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@Na3iL then made the suggestion for an Ubucon. "Why don't we plan for an Ubuncon?" He asked. He followed that nicely enough with definition of the term Ubucon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"An Ubucon is generally an informal, lightly structured gathering of Ubunteros. There are also other meetings and UbuntuConferences"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this juncture, things were beginning to wound up as the chairperson of the meeting, @Na3iL moved the motion for "Elect chairperson for next meeting". This was about the quickest thing to be concluded as there was an immediate unanimous re-election of @Na3iL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final motion for the day was for the selection of a date for the next meeting. Someone suggested that this be treated in the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; as a way to get people to use the list. Thus, everyone agreed that the date for next meeting be decided in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the name of the user who came in at this time deserves a mention. It was @d3r1ck -- we didn't get their full identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] The word "nuxers" is a portmanteau of the words "Linux" and "users".&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] The nicks don't need the preceeding '@'. It's used here for emphasis.&lt;/h5&gt;</content><category term="irc"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="africa"></category><category term="ubuntu africa"></category><category term="meeting"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry><entry><title>To be Forearmed is to be Help-ready</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/article/readying-for-net-help.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-15T12:10:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-15T12:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-15:/article/readying-for-net-help.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are seeking programming help, then do your homework or your potential helpers might raise eyebrows.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I felt compelled to write this after my personal experience trying to get help with my code on IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love to make the computer do things exactly the way we want, so some of us choose to take the bold step of learning to communicate with the machine. And it is not uncommon to find many of our burgeoning kind go from &lt;em&gt;location to location on the web space&lt;/em&gt; trying to get help along the way. We are prompt to ask questions when we sight help.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you learn to program, you are often encouraged to &lt;strong&gt;learn by doing.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain of computer programming or software development is a very practical one. Before now, I had carried this very principle everywhere with me -- in fact, preached it -- but hadn't really put it to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about learning languages (or technologies) by reading big manuals is that, often times, beginners will approach the process like they would any other literature book. But that is clearly a wrong approach as empirical evidence has shown. You don't read these things to simply stomach them. Instead, you swallow and then post-process. In essence, you ruminate over stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, the only way you can really process what you read is to &lt;strong&gt;try things out and see results for yourself&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeks ago, while building an app, I visited IRC frequently to ask questions on just about everything that was unclear to me. While this mode of communication and seeking help is encouraged, abuse of it is strongly discouraged. The good guys over on the IRC channels get pissed off when it appears you're boycotting available resources like documentation, preferring to be spoonfed the whole time. (Remember this is not &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, where the philosophy is for you to ask more and more questions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the sort of thing that happened to me when I began &lt;em&gt;flooding&lt;/em&gt; the channels with my persistent querying. Most of the time the IRC folks kept pointing me to the documentation, as workarounds for most of the issues I had were already documented. A lot of things became much clearer when I decided to finally &lt;a href="https://readthedocs.org/"&gt;read-the-docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I learn from that? &lt;strong&gt;"Do your own research!"&lt;/strong&gt; It's so easy to skip this part, but if you make efforts at finding things out for yourself, you'll be surprised at how much you can dig out without having to bug people. However, this does not guarantee that even the few important questions you'll ask may not be met with hostility, but do not let that discourage you. The people who appear to be unwelcoming are doing so only as a way to discourage you from being over-dependent on the channel.
Another advantage of finding things for yourself is that, you learn the &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and not just the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's fair to quote &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/about/"&gt;Armin Ronacher&lt;/a&gt; here,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"And it's not just asking questions; questioning other people, like what other people do or what you do yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, the worst parts in all of my libraries are where I took the design from somewhere else. And it's not because I know better, it's because pretty much everything everybody does at any point in time has some sort of design decision behind it ... that major decision process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So someone came up with a solution for a particular problem, and he thought about it and then wrote it down. But if you look at someone else's design, you might no longer understand why the decision was made in the first place. And ... in fact, if the original implementation is ten years old, who knows if the design ideas behind it are still entirely correct."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Personally, I like to answer questions and help put people on track. Nonetheless, if the queries got too overwhelming -- especially coming from the same person -- I would eventually lose interest in answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let me remind you of some &lt;strong&gt;tidbits or etiquettes of IRC&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construct your questions well (concise, well written and straight-to-the-point questions are more likely to attract help)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't EVER post code in a channel! &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pastebin"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it and share the link in the channel instead. While at it, don't post your entire code (unless you specifically need to). Post only the relevant portion -- the one you have an issue with. The only exception to this is if the snippet of code is considerably short, say one or two lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be overly respectful. Yes, dont be too respectful -- &lt;em&gt;cut all the 'Sirs'&lt;/em&gt;. Only be moderately polite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure you have and use a registered nick. This gives you an identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last one is entirely my opinion but it's also based on what I have observed. &lt;strong&gt;Don't just be a leech, try to contribute to the community&lt;/strong&gt;. Answer questions when you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do you look to before looking to IRC? There are three sources you may &lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt; from before turning to internet-relay-chat for help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. * Documentation is the manual the creator or experts of a software product or tool provide their users with. So you want to know the ins and outs of a technology? That's the right place to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read blog posts&lt;/strong&gt; related to your topic-area. Blog posts are often based on people's experiences, so you're likely to find help from there, especially if the writer has faced the same issue. Remember to &lt;code&gt;bookmark&lt;/code&gt; the really helpful ones as you go ;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last and very important. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/learn-to-read-the-source-luke/"&gt;Read the source code!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This is two-fold: First is actually looking into your own code carefully and seeing what syntax or semantic errors you might have made. Secondly, you look into the original code of libraries/frameworks you are using if they are open source, otherwise revert to documentation. With this, you have it all stripped to its bare bones. Point blank! The source code reveals everything you need to know, once you know how to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So why not arm yourself properly before going to post that question. That way, you would not only make it easier to get help [for yourself], but you would be better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] Some Pastebin platforms I use:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastebin.com"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.ubuntu.com"&gt;Ubuntu Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastie.org"&gt;Pastie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.pound-python.org"&gt;Spacepaste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.linux.chat"&gt;##Linux on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; provides a platform which supports version-controlled pastes: &lt;a href="http://gist.github/com"&gt;Github Gists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Because &lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt; heavily depends on Javascript, some people have complained of text-rendering issues possibly arising from browser-compatibility issues with it. So take caution using it. That said, I love its ease-of-use. It supports the use of keyboard shortcuts such as &lt;code&gt;[Ctrl]+[S]&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="irc"></category><category term="help"></category><category term="programming"></category><category term="beginner"></category><category term="pastebin"></category><category term="documentation"></category><category term="practice"></category><category term="dev"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry></feed>