<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log(); - meeting</title><link href="http://tosinmash.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tosinmash.com/feeds/meeting.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tosinmash.com/</id><updated>2016-02-26T12:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The First Python-Nigeria Meetup</title><link href="http://tosinmash.com/article/python-nigeria-first-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-23T13:40:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-26T12:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:tosinmash.com,2016-02-23:/article/python-nigeria-first-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Pythonistas in Nigeria came together to discuss the growth of the Python community in Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The members of the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;Python-Nigeria mailing list&lt;/a&gt; got together for a maiden edition of meetups geared towards growing the Python community in Nigeria. The meeting had about thirty people in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/Co6BPKC"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/Co6BPKCl.jpg?1" title="Python-Nigeria Meetup: Olabayo conducting the meeting" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Prior to the meeting, a few members had discussed the purpose and agenda for the meeting in the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mailing list hasn't exactly been interactive as most members often resought to reading the digests without responding. This was one of the issues the meeting sought to address: to encourage members to participate more actively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was conducted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/olabayo96"&gt;Olabayo Onile-Ere&lt;/a&gt; the moderator of the mailing list. Olabayo is the co-founder of &lt;a href="https://www.hotelsnperks.com/"&gt;Hotels &amp;amp; Perks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olabayo welcomed attendees and explained that the goal was for this group to become the driving force for the emerging Python community in Nigeria. He highlighted the need for more people to join the community, and brought up the topic of organizing a Python conference in Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizer of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DjangoGirlsLAG"&gt;Django Girls Lagos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/windhoek/"&gt;Django Girls Windhoek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AishaXBello"&gt;Aisha Bello&lt;/a&gt; was invited to share her opinion having recently attended &lt;a href="http://na.pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon Namibia&lt;/a&gt; where she delivered a &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/aishab/my-journey-through-python-1"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;. She suggested we first organize a mini Nigerian Python conference to test the waters and sensitize people towards a full blown &lt;strong&gt;PyCon&lt;/strong&gt; that would follow. Narrating her experience in Namibia, she noted that the community over there has made efforts to &lt;em&gt;take programming to the uninitiated&lt;/em&gt;. Okay more seriously, they teach Python programming to secondary school students in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also pointed out that there haven't been many PyCons in Africa; the only ones having held in South Africa and Namibia. It was interesting to know that Nigerias' would be the first in West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a consensus; it was just as Aisha had suggested. A committee (made up of volunteers) was then setup to begin planning towards the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Several members had the opportunity to address the audience during the meeting which lasted for over an hour. Notable among those who spoke was &lt;a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/206213543/iChux.html"&gt;Chukwudi&lt;/a&gt;, a very experienced Python programmer. In his words, &lt;em&gt;"I have been coding in Python everyday since 2004, except when I was sick and couldn't do anything."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href="http://imgur.com/TO2IbXE"&gt;&lt;img src="http://i.imgur.com/TO2IbXEl.jpg" title="Python-Nigeria Meetup: Chukwudi addressing the audience" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In his 12 years of Python programming, Chuks as he's fondly called, has co-reviewed a Python book and has worked in Ibadan for about 10 years. He now resides in Lagos with his family. He talked about some of the projects he's worked on, including a robot that would stealthily index all &lt;strong&gt;".ng"&lt;/strong&gt; domains. He expressed his delight at finally getting to meet and possibly work with others in this Python space. He closed his speech saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Python is something I code and breathe. It's a lovely language. You are welcome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
One short presentation I particularly enjoyed was that of Dipo Odumosu about his work for the &lt;a href="http://www.population.gov.ng/"&gt;National Population Commission&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.unicef.org/"&gt;UNICEF&lt;/a&gt;. They have an &lt;a href="http://br.rapidsmsnigeria.org/"&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; that is used to track birth statistics in all local governments in the country. He described it as a conceptually simple app, but one that sort of has a bit of everything: built with &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.rapidsms.org/"&gt;RapidSMS&lt;/a&gt;; a little scientific and a little regular &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt;; and aggregation is done using &lt;a href="http://pandas.pydata.org/"&gt;Pandas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also spoke about their recurrent challenge with number crunching on large cumulative data, welcoming suggestions from the audience as to tackling the issue. As we were constrained by time, discussion on the issue will continue in the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or the newly setup &lt;a href="https://pythonnigeria.slack.com/"&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
First year student at &lt;a href="http://www.oauife.edu.ng/"&gt;OAU Ife&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Olamyy_Fadil"&gt;Lekan Wahab&lt;/a&gt;, who has been coding since secondary school stepped up to share his campus experience with the house. Explaining how his admission into the university was met with the disappointment of a non-existent programmer community, and how that inspired him to setup one by introducing his colleagues to the Python programming language,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Before I got to school, I had this idea that I was going to meet quite a lot of programmers on campus, but I was very disappointed. The only other programmer in my class was a Java coder, and he said when he got to &lt;em&gt;'if'&lt;/em&gt;, the stuff got really hard and he just dropped it; he said he wasn't interested in it anymore. Then I took it upon myself to start a club; I started Python Club in OAU."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Personally, not only did I find this impressive, but it was even more exciting to learn of the amazing projects Lekan's group had been able to work on; projects including a home automation system built with the &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.arduino.cc/"&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt; amd mobile devices, a payment/airtime recharge service and a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking further, Lekan used the medium to solicit support towards a forthcoming &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/"&gt;Django Girls&lt;/a&gt; workshop organised by his club. The workshop is slated for April at Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife. &lt;strong&gt;Volunteer mentors/coaches are needed for the workshop.&lt;/strong&gt; Kindly &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/oau/"&gt;visit this link&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the items on the agenda for the evening was to come up with an idea for an open source application that the group would collaboratively work on. Olabayo welcomed interesting ideas from the audience, and these two came up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/peterayeni_"&gt;Peter Ayeni&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;a href="http://www.gigcabal.com/"&gt;GigCabal&lt;/a&gt;, who came all the way from Abuja suggested that we work on a site analytics/ratings service for Nigerian websites. He likened this with existing platforms like &lt;a href="http://www.alexa.com/"&gt;Alexa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Olamilec"&gt;Olamilekan Adeniji&lt;/a&gt;, creator of &lt;a href="https://vc4a.com/ventures/mergency/"&gt;mErgencyNG&lt;/a&gt;, explained the idea behind his product and suggested that we work on it collectively. The app will provide a platform for citizens to report crime/suspicions to appropriate agencies or radio corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poll was conducted, and the house voted in favor of mErgencyNG. It was at this point that Chuks once again spoke and offered to open-source a library he had developed for analysing errors, in an effort to spark some creativity among the Pythonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To encourage members even further, Olabayo read out a recent &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-nigeria/2016-February/000068.html"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/naomiceder"&gt;Naomi Ceder&lt;/a&gt;, the lady who had been moderating the mailing list, until just before the meeting when she passed this duty on to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, Olabayo designated the task of setting up a Slack community for the group to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eEyitemi"&gt;Eyitemi Gbejule&lt;/a&gt;, which he promptly did. The community is now active at &lt;a href="http://pythonnigeria.slack.com"&gt;pythonnigeria.slack.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was it. Thanks were in order (especially to &lt;a href="http://cchubnigeria.com/"&gt;CcHub&lt;/a&gt; and organizers of Django Girls Lagos). The meeting was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can join the &lt;a href="http://pythonnigeria.slack.com"&gt;Python-Nigeria Slack community&lt;/a&gt; by subscribing to the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; at:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and sending an email requesting an invite to:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;python-nigeria@python.org
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="meetup"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python nigeria"></category><category term="mailing list"></category><category term="nigeria"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="meeting"></category><category term="slack"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry><entry><title>Ubuntu Africa Calls</title><link href="http://tosinmash.com/article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-02-01T05:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2016-02-03T14:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:tosinmash.com,2016-02-01:/article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Communities drive growth. Ubuntu Africa is for all Linux and Ubuntu users in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h4&gt;This post is about the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa community's&lt;/a&gt; meeting that held in their &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;IRC channel&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday the 26th of January, 2016&lt;/em&gt;. You could read the raw logs of the meeting &lt;a href="http://52.17.74.45/freenode-%23ubuntu-africa/2016-01-27-18-31-20.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but my guess is that reading logs like that might not be the most enjoyable task for your eyes. So I have tried to make this blog post a more pleasant-for-the-eyes version of it. :)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa&lt;/a&gt; is a community of Ubuntu (and Linux) users within the shores of the African continent. There are several local communities (&lt;em&gt;LoCos&lt;/em&gt;) specific to countries, but this group is limited only to the continent. It aims to bring together these LoCos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that coming together to work together will bring about a more rapid growth. Owing to our disparate skills individually, we need communities like this that will present us with people who are skilled in the areas that we are lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the &lt;a href="http://loco.ubuntu.com/teams/"&gt;directory of Ubuntu LoCos&lt;/a&gt;, I find it a little surprising that there are no efforts for an active community in my home country, Nigeria. Many people I have met scarcely even know about &lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/InternetRelayChat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; around here. More so with the coming of &lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recent foray into the African developer community had informed me about this event a few days earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes before the meeting, some users (myself inclusive) had arrived the IRC channel and engaged in discussions while patiently waiting for the scheduled meeting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting began at the set time. And it was, as it was customary, chaired by a user whom had been elected in the last meeting Naeil Zoueidi (@Na3iL)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from Tunisia. The other person who seemed to have some good footing in the house was Miles Sharp (@Kilos)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the meeting came from different African nations including Cameroon (with the highest population and mostly first-timers), Tunisia, South Africa, Ghana, Zimbabwe, RDC and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary language used during discussion was English. However, Kilos pointed out that if any user struggled with the English language, they could use their own language (most likely French) in the hope that someone would translate for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt; IRC channel has a bot called &lt;strong&gt;QA&lt;/strong&gt; that logs meetings and does a few other tasks. At the beginning of meetings attending users are expected to introduce themselves using the format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When a user does this correctly, the bot would respond to the user confirming receipt of the information. This is doable anytime during the meeting. So if a user comes in late, that's the first thing they'd be expected to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that the bot performs no parsing whatsoever on this given data and just logs it as is. Therefore, it's in a user's best interest to adhere (strictly) to the format given above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Before the meeting, there had been an &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/AfricanTeams/Meetings/20160127"&gt;agenda page&lt;/a&gt; -- I believe this was open for suggestions on the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; -- iterating the issues to be discussed at the meeting. And this was strictly followed during the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Meeting Excerpts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;The Ubuntu Africa community is currently an unofficial group. It would need more activity to gain the official recognition.&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it is important to note that all members have a mandate to try and convince users from African Linux local communities/user-groups to join the Ubuntu Africa community whilst still being active in their respective communities, as this community is country-agnostic and aims to bring us all under one umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting had a number of first-timers (myself included) in attendance. The new members were recognised. And we learnt of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/CameroonianTeam/NewMembers/en"&gt;Ubuntu local community in Cameroon&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/mailman/listinfo/ubuntu-cm"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users were encouraged to get word out about the fledgling community through their social hangouts (Facebook, Twitter and the rest...). More suggestions came in on how to  get the publicizing done. Users suggested YouTube videos, Twitter posts (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt;) and blog posts (like the one you are reading now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement was that Pieter Engelbrecht (@chesedo) from South Africa would &lt;s&gt;put up the blog post.&lt;/s&gt; create a tweet about the community using the hashtag &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;"#ubuntu-africa"&lt;/a&gt;. And just in case you want to help get the word out too, here's the link to share: http://ubuntu-africa.info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chair of the meeting raised a point about making some improvements to the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info"&gt;current website of the community&lt;/a&gt; -- adding a blog section to it. This brought our attention to the designer of the current portal, Raoul Snyman (@superfly) from South Africa and due thanks were accorded by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@superfly revealed that the current site was implemented using the static blog generator, &lt;em&gt;Nikola&lt;/em&gt;, meaning it already comes with a blogging feature, although it hadn't yet been activated, since no one had been available to blog on the site. @Na3iL offered to help with the blogging, and in the end it was agreed that the task would be handled collaboratively by @superfly (technically) and @Na3iL (literarily).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Mawutor Donkor from Ghana (@mawutor) made one final suggestion in this regard about getting involved in Ubuntu-Lab projects for schools as a way to gain some media attention.. Their suggestion was commended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to something more technical. Another memeber of the group Cameroonian member @ongolaBoy talked about the issues surrounding approval of our mirror. He stated that the status of submission had gone from "pending" to "unofficial", which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shared the URL to the Launchpad page of the mirror: https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+mirror/miroir.cm.auf.org-archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone was impressed with this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last topic tended toward "social" again, and it was kick-started by the chair with the question, "Any new coming events?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilos mentioned the upcoming release of Ubuntu 16.04, which we all anticipate for April. The Tunisian folks (@Na3iL and @elacheche_anis) got talking about some SysAdmin workshop still in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@Na3iL then made the suggestion for an Ubucon. "Why don't we plan for an Ubuncon?" He asked. He followed that nicely enough with definition of the term Ubucon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"An Ubucon is generally an informal, lightly structured gathering of Ubunteros. There are also other meetings and UbuntuConferences"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this juncture, things were beginning to wound up as the chairperson of the meeting, @Na3iL moved the motion for "Elect chairperson for next meeting". This was about the quickest thing to be concluded as there was an immediate unanimous re-election of @Na3iL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final motion for the day was for the selection of a date for the next meeting. Someone suggested that this be treated in the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; as a way to get people to use the list. Thus, everyone agreed that the date for next meeting be decided in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the name of the user who came in at this time deserves a mention. It was @d3r1ck -- we didn't get their full identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] The word "nuxers" is a portmanteau of the words "Linux" and "users".&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] The nicks don't need the preceeding '@'. It's used here for emphasis.&lt;/h5&gt;</content><category term="irc"></category><category term="ubuntu"></category><category term="africa"></category><category term="ubuntu africa"></category><category term="meeting"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry></feed>