<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log(); - München</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/munchen.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2019-04-12T01:30:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>&gt;&gt;&gt; 'acetakwas' in pyconweb.speakers</title><link href="/article/goto-pyconweb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-04-07T13:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-04-12T01:30:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:None,2019-04-07:/article/goto-pyconweb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;München, München, hier komme ich!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not big on festivities or rituals, but this year's &lt;strong&gt;Feb-14th day&lt;/strong&gt; presented me 
a wonderful "opportunity", which I was quick to seize by the throat. It was an 
&lt;em&gt;early&lt;/em&gt; early-bird-tickets announcement. But more importantly, it was also a 
notification of the closing window on 
&lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-does-call-for-papers-mean"&gt;CFPs&lt;/a&gt; within the 24 
hours to follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, I felt quite optimistic about a possible chance to speak, and 
quickly put together the draft for a talk proposal. To get someone to review, I hit 
&lt;a href="https://discord.gg/J8pyRdj"&gt;Pallets Projects' Discord&lt;/a&gt; and reached out to 
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/davidism"&gt;davidism&lt;/a&gt;, who was kind enough to indulge me. A 
few minutes on and I was good to go; and so it was that I put-in something of a 
nick-of-time submission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I informed &lt;em&gt;the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yinye_m"&gt;lady&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, as I am wont to do. 
And with our phalanges kept crossed, we wrapped up in cloaks of hope. I received 
the first feedback some 12 days later.&lt;a href="#footnote"&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Then, in another 11 
days (on March 09), the notification about the talk's selection arrived. &lt;em&gt;Woot!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Event Program." src="/article/images/pyconweb-program-werkzeug-acetakwas.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that come &lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/#program"&gt;26th May, 2019&lt;/a&gt;[&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;], 
I will be given some 30 minutes before an audience at &lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/"&gt;PyConWeb&lt;/a&gt;, 
for a presentation on one of the nifty tools contained in the arsenal of 
&lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/"&gt;Pallets Projects&lt;/a&gt;: the &lt;strong&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/strong&gt; library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/p/werkzeug/"&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/a&gt;, which I'd much rather refer 
to as the WSGI swiss-army knife, is one of those brilliant pieces of software 
out there that have enjoyed little attention. Permit me to blame the 
unpopularity of Werkzeug on the fame of Flask, which is what most people 
interface with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/about/"&gt;Armin Ronacher&lt;/a&gt;, whom I admire so much, and 
who, over the years, has created an &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/projects/"&gt;army of useful tools&lt;/a&gt; 
across a spectrum of language ecosystems, created Werkzeug in 2007. This was 
three years before the birth of &lt;a href="https://palletsprojects.com/p/flask/"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;, 
which, built on Werkzeug, has become the quintessential Python microframework 
for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My talk is titled: &lt;strong&gt;Werkzeug: What's in it for me?&lt;/strong&gt; It will take the audience 
on a subliminal, revelatory journey that will unearth the most kept secrets of 
the "underweb". &lt;em&gt;Okay, not quite. ;)&lt;/em&gt; You can pretty much think of it as a simple 
introduction to the &lt;em&gt;good parts&lt;/em&gt; of the Werkzeug toolset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have ever touched Flask, then you have certainly used Werkzeug. But the 
distinction must be made that, while Flask is a framework, Werkzeug is a library.
While you might interact with the Flask API as a developer, Flask talks to the web 
server quite easily by leveraging the Werkzeug API. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Werkzeug, on the other hand, cannot be spoken about without the mention of 
&lt;a href="https://wsgi.readthedocs.io/en/latest/"&gt;WSGI&lt;/a&gt;, which is, essentially, what it 
wraps. Bundling a lot of WSGI utilities out-of-the-box, Werkzeug provides a lot of 
the core apparatus for building or working-with a Python web framework at the low 
level. In fact, if you happen to know a thing or two about the &lt;a href=""&gt;early-day 
struggles with web programming in Python and how WSGI came forth as the silver 
bullet that alleviated all of our web-server communication problems&lt;/a&gt;, then you 
would be quick to laud the efforts of Armin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/"&gt;PyConWeb, Munich&lt;/a&gt; is a niche PyCon event. So rather than be a 
generic &lt;a href="http://pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon event&lt;/a&gt; like many others, the organisers have 
chosen to take a rather different and interesting approach by narrowing the 
scope of the event to web technologies. I do not currently know of a more 
perfect event at which to have a talk on Werkzeug delivered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I find it an interesting coincidence that the name 
&lt;a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Werkzeug#Etymology"&gt;Werkzeug&lt;/a&gt; has its roots in 
the German language, having the meaning "work stuff".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's it for now. It's back to prepping for München, for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liebe Grüße,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;TosinMash&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr id="footnote"/&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much commendation for the &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/pyconweb"&gt;PyConWeb&lt;/a&gt; organising team for their &lt;em&gt;extreme&lt;/em&gt; niceness all the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct link to my talk. The link appears to be inconsistently broken: 
&lt;a href="https://pyconweb.com/talks/26-05-2019/werkzeug-whats-in-it-for-me"&gt;https://pyconweb.com/talks/26-05-2019/werkzeug-whats-in-it-for-me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="talk"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="presentation"></category><category term="werkzeug"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="pallets"></category><category term="pocoo"></category><category term="public speaking"></category><category term="armin ronacher"></category><category term="München"></category><category term="Munich"></category><category term="Germany"></category></entry></feed>