<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>acetakwas.log();</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://takwas.github.io/feeds/slack.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://takwas.github.io/</id><updated>2016-02-23T16:10:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>The First Python-Nigeria Meetup</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/article/python-nigeria-first-meetup.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-23T16:10:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-02-23:article/python-nigeria-first-meetup.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The members of the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;Python-Nigeria mailing list&lt;/a&gt; got together for a maiden edition of meetups geared towards growing the Python community in Nigeria. The meeting had about thirty people in attendance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the meeting, a few members had discussed the purpose and agenda for the meeting in the mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mailing list hasn't exactly been interactive as most members often resought to reading the digests without responding. This was one of the issues the meeting sought to address: to encourage members to participate more actively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting was conducted by &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/olabayo96"&gt;Olabayo Onile-Ere&lt;/a&gt; the moderator of the mailing list. Olabayo is the co-founder of &lt;a href="https://www.hotelsnperks.com/"&gt;Hotels &amp;amp; Perks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olabayo welcomed attendees and explained that the goal was for this group to become the driving force for the emerging Python community in Nigeria. He highlighted the need for more people to join the community, and brought up the topic of organizing a Python conference in Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizer of &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DjangoGirlsLAG"&gt;Django Girls Lagos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/windhoek/"&gt;Django Girls Windhoek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AishaXBello"&gt;Aisha Bello&lt;/a&gt; was invited to share her opinion having recently attended &lt;a href="http://na.pycon.org/"&gt;PyCon Namibia&lt;/a&gt; where she delivered a &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/aishab/my-journey-through-python-1"&gt;talk&lt;/a&gt;. She suggested we first organize a mini Nigerian Python conference to test the waters and sensitize people towards a full blown &lt;strong&gt;PyCon&lt;/strong&gt; that would follow. Narrating her experience in Namibia, she noted that the community over there has made efforts to &lt;em&gt;take programming to the uninitiated&lt;/em&gt;. Okay more seriously, they teach Python programming to secondary school students in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also pointed out that there haven't been many PyCons in Africa; the only ones having held in South Africa and Namibia. It was interesting to know that Nigerias' would be the first in West Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a consensus, it was just as Aisha had suggested. A committee (made up of volunteers) was then setup to begin planning towards the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Several members had the opportunity to address the audience during the meeting which lasted for over an hour. Notable among those who spoke was &lt;a href="https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/206213543/iChux.html"&gt;Chukwudi&lt;/a&gt;, a very experienced Python programmer. In his words, &lt;em&gt;"I have been coding in Python everyday since 2004, except when I was sick and couldn't do anything."&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his 12 years of Python programming, Chuks as he's fondly called, has co-reviewed a Python book and has worked in Ibadan for about 10 years. He now resides in Lagos with his family. He talked about some of the projects he's worked on, including a robot that would stealthily index all &lt;strong&gt;".ng"&lt;/strong&gt; domains. He expressed his delight at finally getting to meet and possibly work with others in this Python space. He closed his speech saying,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Python is something I code and breathe. It's a lovely language. You are welcome."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One short presentation I particularly enjoyed was that of Dean Paul about his work for the &lt;a href="http://www.population.gov.ng/"&gt;National Population Commission&lt;/a&gt; in collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.unicef.org/"&gt;UNICEF&lt;/a&gt;. They have an &lt;a href="http://br.rapidsmsnigeria.org/"&gt;application&lt;/a&gt; that is used to track birth statistics in all local governments in the country. He described it as a conceptually simple app, but one that sort of has a bit of everything: built with &lt;a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.rapidsms.org/"&gt;RapidSMS&lt;/a&gt;; a little scientific and a little regular &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Create,_read,_update_and_delete"&gt;CRUD&lt;/a&gt;; and aggregation is done using &lt;a href="http://pandas.pydata.org/"&gt;Pandas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also spoke about their recurrent challenge with number crunching on large cumulative data, welcoming suggestions from the audience as to tackling the issue. As we were constrained by time, discussion on the issue will continue in the &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or the newly setup &lt;a href="https://pythonnigeria.slack.com/"&gt;Slack community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
First year student at OAU Ife, Lekan Wahab, who has been coding since secondary school stepped up to share his campus experience with the house. Explaining how his admission into the university was met with the disappointment of a non-existent programmer community, and how that inspired him to setup one by introducing his colleagues to the Python programming language,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Before I got to school, I had this idea that I was going to meet quite a lot of programmers on campus, but I was very disappointed. The only other programmer in my class was a Java coder, and he said when he got to &lt;em&gt;'if'&lt;/em&gt;, the stuff got really hard and he just dropped it; he said he wasn't interested in it anymore. Then I took it upon myself to start a club; I started Python Club."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, not only did I find this impressive, but it was even more exciting to learn of the amazing projects Lekan's group had been able to work on; projects including a home automation system built with the &lt;a href="https://www.raspberrypi.org/"&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.arduino.cc/"&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt; amd mobile devices, a payment/airtime recharge service and a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One of the items on the agenda for the evening was to come up with an idea for an open source application that the group would collaboratively work on. Olabayo welcomed interesting ideas from the audience, and these two came up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/peterayeni_"&gt;Peter Ayeni&lt;/a&gt;, founder of &lt;a href="http://www.gigcabal.com/"&gt;GigCabal&lt;/a&gt;, who came all the way from Abuja suggested that we work on a site analytics/ratings service for Nigerian websites. He likened this with existing platforms like &lt;a href="http://www.alexa.com/"&gt;Alexa&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.webalizer.org/"&gt;Webalizer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Olamilec"&gt;Olamilekan Adeniji&lt;/a&gt;, creator of &lt;a href="https://vc4a.com/ventures/mergency/"&gt;mErgencyNG&lt;/a&gt;, explained the idea behind his product and suggested that we work on it collectively. The app will provide a platform for citizens to report crime/suspicions to appropriate agencies or radio corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A poll was conducted, and the house voted in favor of eMergencyNG. It was at this point that Chuks once again spoke and offered to open-source a library he had developed for analysing errors, in an effort to spark some creativity among the Pythonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
To encourage members even further, Olabayo read out a recent &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-nigeria/2016-February/000068.html"&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/naomiceder"&gt;Naomi Ceder&lt;/a&gt;, the lady who had been moderating the mailing list, until just before the meeting when she passed this duty on to him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, Olabayo designated the task of setting up a Slack community for the group to &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/eEyitemi"&gt;Eyitemi Gbejule&lt;/a&gt;, which he promptly did. The community is now active at &lt;a href="http://pythonnigeria.slack.com"&gt;pythonnigeria.slack.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was it. Thanks were in order (especially to &lt;a href="http://cchubnigeria.com/"&gt;CcHub&lt;/a&gt; and organizers of Django Girls Lagos). The meeting was over.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="meetup"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="python nigeria"></category><category term="mailing list"></category><category term="nigeria"></category><category term="pycon"></category><category term="meeting"></category><category term="slack"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry><entry><title>Slack is Tweak-friendly</title><link href="http://takwas.github.io/article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-12-25T23:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</name></author><id>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-25:article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I migrated the locked default channel on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is a communication platform built for teams. While it is free by default, there are features reserved for paid users. However, the free version already comes with a ton of cool features, and is highly usable as is, especially for teams that are relatively small. My team has stuck with this unpaid version of the application for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we decided to have our clients join our Slack team, with some envisaged benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would ease the process of keeping the client up-to-date on project progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would bring our clients to our preferred communication platform, bringing them all in one place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could leverage some of the many tools available for use with Slack to improve our communication with clients. It's worth noting that Slack is very API friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In doing this, we were presented with a small challenge. All of our previous conversations which had mostly being in the public, general channel, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, were now open to our newly signed-on client. Some of these conversations obviously included stuff we would rather be more privy about. This meant I had to quickly find a way to &lt;em&gt;migrate&lt;/em&gt; -- I chose not to &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; -- the messages in the hope that he had not scrolled back through the channel's message log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have been easier if Slack allowed certain modifications to the default channel named &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For instance, Slack prevents the deletion of this channel. On top of that, Slack puts some restrictions on private channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/213185307-Deleting-a-channel"&gt;deleted, but can be &lt;em&gt;archived&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be changed to &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; channels even though the reverse is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These limitations notwithstanding, the following explains my approach to tackling the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I used Slack's &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201658943-Exporting-your-team-s-Slack-history"&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; feature to backup all of our conversations, including channel information. A caveat here is, &lt;em&gt;Slack does not include private channels' data with exported data by default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but thankfully, we hadn't any private rooms at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Slack exports team data in JSON format, making it very easy to work with. Having downloaded the exported data, I started looking through it for parts that I could tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some top-level (&lt;strong&gt;root folder&lt;/strong&gt;) files which included meta-data about users, teams and channels. Then there were also folders for each channel, in which, conversation logs were kept, grouped by days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I edited the &lt;code&gt;channels.json&lt;/code&gt; file in the top-level directory, and changed the name of the channel &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;, which contained the messages, to some new name. Then I went and renamed the folder named &lt;code&gt;general&lt;/code&gt;, to this new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these changes in place, I compressed the modified files alongside the unmodified ones into a &lt;em&gt;zip&lt;/em&gt; archive; the original Slack-exported data had come in a zip file as well. Slack allows you to &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201748703-Importing-message-history"&gt;import&lt;/a&gt; this zip file into your Slack team, which was what I did next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the import, Slack automatically tried to match detected channels (from the import) with existing ones, after-which I was presented with a page that displayed the mapping suggestions. I simply set it not to map but create new channels instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful completion of the imports, I went on to delete all the messages in the existing &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt; channel. Those messages were now the contents of a newly minted channel, created using the new name I previously gave to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these in place, I did two more things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I edited and marked the new channel as &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I welcomed our new client to our Slack space &lt;strong&gt;;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] More on Slack's default channel - #general&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] Exporting private data from Slack&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="slack"></category><category term="configuration"></category><category term="json"></category><category term="general"></category><category term="backup"></category><category term="communication"></category><category term="planet"></category></entry></feed>