<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>acetakwas.log();</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/</link><description>while True: print    &lt;strong&gt;\&lt;/strong&gt;</description><atom:link href="http://takwas.github.io/feeds/tosin-damilare-james-animashaun.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:59:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ubuntu Africa Calls</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html</link><description>&lt;h4&gt;This post is about the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa community's&lt;/a&gt; meeting that held in their &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;IRC channel&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;em&gt;Wednesday the 26th of January, 2016&lt;/em&gt;. You could read the raw logs of the meeting &lt;a href="http://52.17.74.45/freenode-%23ubuntu-africa/2016-01-27-18-31-20.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, but my guess is that reading logs like that might not be the most enjoyable task for your eyes. So I have tried to make this blog post a more pleasant-for-the-eyes version of it. :)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/"&gt;Ubuntu Africa&lt;/a&gt; is a community of Ubuntu (and Linux) users within the shores of the African continent. There are several local communities (&lt;em&gt;LoCos&lt;/em&gt;) specific to countries, but this group is limited only to the continent. It aims to bring together these LoCos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We believe that coming together to work together will bring about a more rapid growth. Owing to our disparate skills individually, we need communities like this that will present us with people who are skilled in the areas that we are lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking through the &lt;a href="http://loco.ubuntu.com/teams/"&gt;directory of Ubuntu LoCos&lt;/a&gt;, I find it a little surprising that there are no efforts for an active community in my home country, Nigeria. Many people I have met scarcely even know about &lt;a href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/InternetRelayChat"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; around here. More so with the coming of &lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recent foray into the African developer community had informed me about this event a few days earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minutes before the meeting, some users (myself inclusive) had arrived the IRC channel and engaged in discussions while patiently waiting for the scheduled meeting time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting began at the set time. And it was, as it was customary, chaired by a user whom had been elected in the last meeting Naeil Zoueidi (@Na3iL)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from Tunisia. The other person who seemed to have some good footing in the house was Miles Sharp (@Kilos)&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; from South Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the meeting came from different African nations including Cameroon (with the highest population and mostly first-timers), Tunisia, South Africa, Ghana, Zimbabwe, RDC and Nigeria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary language used during discussion was English. However, Kilos pointed out that if any user struggled with the English language, they could use their own language (most likely French) in the hope that someone would translate for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info/chat-with-us.html"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt; IRC channel has a bot called &lt;strong&gt;QA&lt;/strong&gt; that logs meetings and does a few other tasks. At the beginning of meetings attending users are expected to introduce themselves using the format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;OR&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;QA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;am&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;country&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When a user does this correctly, the bot would respond to the user confirming receipt of the information. This is doable anytime during the meeting. So if a user comes in late, that's the first thing they'd be expected to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have noticed that the bot performs no parsing whatsoever on this given data and just logs it as is. Therefore, it's in a user's best interest to adhere (strictly) to the format given above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Before the meeting, there had been an &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/AfricanTeams/Meetings/20160127"&gt;agenda page&lt;/a&gt; -- I believe this was open for suggestions on the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; -- iterating the issues to be discussed at the meeting. And this was strictly followed during the meeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Meeting Excerpts&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;The Ubuntu Africa community is currently an unofficial group. It would need more activity to gain the official recognition.&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, it is important to note that all members have a mandate to try and convince users from African Linux local communities/user-groups to join the Ubuntu Africa community whilst still being active in their respective communities, as this community is country-agnostic and aims to bring us all under one umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting had a number of first-timers (myself included) in attendance. The new members were recognised. And we learnt of the &lt;a href="https://wiki.ubuntu.com/CameroonianTeam/NewMembers/en"&gt;Ubuntu local community in Cameroon&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href="https://lists.ubuntu.com/mailman/listinfo/ubuntu-cm"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users were encouraged to get word out about the fledgling community through their social hangouts (Facebook, Twitter and the rest...). More suggestions came in on how to  get the publicizing done. Users suggested YouTube videos, Twitter posts (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;#ubuntu-africa&lt;/a&gt;) and blog posts (like the one you are reading now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement was that Pieter Engelbrecht (@chesedo) from South Africa would &lt;s&gt;put up the blog post.&lt;/s&gt; create a tweet about the community using the hashtag &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubuntuAfrica?src=hash"&gt;"#ubuntu-africa"&lt;/a&gt;. And just in case you want to help get the word out too, here's the link to share: http://ubuntu-africa.info&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chair of the meeting raised a point about making some improvements to the &lt;a href="http://ubuntu-africa.info"&gt;current website of the community&lt;/a&gt; -- adding a blog section to it. This brought our attention to the designer of the current portal, Raoul Snyman (@superfly) from South Africa and due thanks were accorded by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@superfly revealed that the current site was implemented using the static blog generator, &lt;em&gt;Nikola&lt;/em&gt;, meaning it already comes with a blogging feature, although it hadn't yet been activated, since no one had been available to blog on the site. @Na3iL offered to help with the blogging, and in the end it was agreed that the task would be handled collaboratively by @superfly (technically) and @Na3iL (literarily).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Mawutor Donkor from Ghana (@mawutor) made one final suggestion in this regard about getting involved in Ubuntu-Lab projects for schools as a way to gain some media attention.. Their suggestion was commended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to something more technical. Another memeber of the group Cameroonian member @ongolaBoy talked about the issues surrounding approval of our mirror. He stated that the status of submission had gone from "pending" to "unofficial", which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They shared the URL to the Launchpad page of the mirror: https://launchpad.net/ubuntu/+mirror/miroir.cm.auf.org-archive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone was impressed with this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last topic tended toward "social" again, and it was kick-started by the chair with the question, "Any new coming events?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kilos mentioned the upcoming release of Ubuntu 16.04, which we all anticipate for April. The Tunisian folks (@Na3iL and @elacheche_anis) got talking about some SysAdmin workshop still in the works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;@Na3iL then made the suggestion for an Ubucon. "Why don't we plan for an Ubuncon?" He asked. He followed that nicely enough with definition of the term Ubucon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"An Ubucon is generally an informal, lightly structured gathering of Ubunteros. There are also other meetings and UbuntuConferences"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this juncture, things were beginning to wound up as the chairperson of the meeting, @Na3iL moved the motion for "Elect chairperson for next meeting". This was about the quickest thing to be concluded as there was an immediate unanimous re-election of @Na3iL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final motion for the day was for the selection of a date for the next meeting. Someone suggested that this be treated in the &lt;a href="https://launchpad.net/~ubuntu-africa"&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; as a way to get people to use the list. Thus, everyone agreed that the date for next meeting be decided in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the name of the user who came in at this time deserves a mention. It was @d3r1ck -- we didn't get their full identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] The word "nuxers" is a portmanteau of the words "Linux" and "users".&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] The nicks don't need the preceeding '@'. It's used here for emphasis.&lt;/h5&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-02-01:article/ubuntu-africa-calls.html</guid><category>irc</category><category>ubuntu</category><category>africa</category><category>ubuntu-africa</category><category>meeting</category><category>project</category><category>planet</category></item><item><title>On the Stellar Train!</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/on-the-stellar-train.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two days ago, I attended Stellar.org's fireside chat at &lt;a href=""&gt;Idea Hub&lt;/a&gt; in Lagos. It was an enlightening event; one that may well be my gateway into the world of open source in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt this will present a somewhat steep learning curve knowing that my background in finance (and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Financial_technology"&gt;FinTech&lt;/a&gt;) is not much to write home about. The experience and payoffs will of course be worth the while and I am expecting more developers to join the train as the platform is still very welcoming at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellar is a fairly new financial technology service that aims to be the de facto way in which we move money around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Stellar's FAQ page,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Stellar is a decentralized protocol you can use to send and receive money in any pair of currencies. So for example, the protocol supports sending money in dollars and having it arrive in pesos."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I particularly like the analogy used &lt;a href="https://techpoint.ng/2016/01/28/how-stellar-kickstart-nigeria-payments-revolution/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; by the Executive Director of Stellar, Joyce Kim,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Stellar platform functions a lot like email whose underlying protocol is SMTP. Before SMTP, you could only email people that were in the same company, network or ISP as you"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
She says it would be a lot like being able to send mails across different mail providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the details of the workings of Stellar are still very unclear to me, but a few things I've been able to make sense of include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellar operates on a decentralized network of servers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellar maintains an open digital ledger of transactions. This data is synchronized on all servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial institutions subscribed to the Stellar service (called gateways, and to act as "trust" houses) can offer Stellar credits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellar credits are used to resolve currency pairing issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Consensus is how Stellar verifies the credibility of a transaction before allowing it to pull through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stellar.org provides an &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.stellar.org/learn/explainers/"&gt;explain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; page to describe these concepts. However, I find &lt;a href="http://thenextweb.com/insider/2014/08/01/stellar-open-source-solution-international-money-transfers-currency/"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; very explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have joined Stellar's public &lt;a href="http://stellar-public.slack.com"&gt;Slack team&lt;/a&gt;. And so far, I've been received with warm arms. I encourage many budding programmers lookig to get their feet wet with open source projects to join this platform and make some contributions. The mantra for me is "even if it fails..." I think this says enough already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment, the project I'm looking to contribute to is the &lt;a href="https://github.com/StellarCN/py-stellar-base"&gt;Python library&lt;/a&gt; for interfacing with the &lt;a href="https://github.com/stellar/stellar-core"&gt;Stellar core&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is still in beta form and could readily use some help. It was suggested to me by Scott Fleckenstein (&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/nullstyle"&gt;@nullstyle&lt;/a&gt;), the first Engineer at Stellar. At the event, Scott tried to work us through the technical nitty-gritties: innerworkings, stack and how-to-get-started with contributing to the Stellar project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just some of the things I have been able to wrap my mind around thus far. I am optimistic that once I tie myself in the loop of working on the code and working with the leads I get from time to time, it would all clear out in due course.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 11:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-31:article/on-the-stellar-train.html</guid><category>stellar</category><category>altcoin</category><category>crytocurrency</category><category>open-source</category><category>project</category><category>planet</category></item><item><title>wGetting Them All!</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/save-web-for-offline.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If you are in a location with internet connection issues, or limited by the amount of bandwidth you can afford, then there are ways you can leverage the resources that are useful to you on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some websites or blogs have content arranged in order of chapters that I like to read in that order. And some others just appeal to me as troves of useful content that I would want to keep within easy reach. The challenge with this is that there are times when I have no active internet subcscription or connection, making such resources unavailable to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, it is possible for me to keep an entire website offline. With the help of some of tools, I could download the site for offline reading! This is &lt;strong&gt;particularly workable with static sites&lt;/strong&gt; that have no interaction with the backend, other than delivering static pages to us -- so don't think of doing this with Facebook, or Quora. &lt;strong&gt;:)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two ways I do this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I use the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.httrack.com/"&gt;HTTrack Website Copier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; software, which is available cross platform; and &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://linux.die.net/man/1/wget"&gt;wget&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, I learnt about this one recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also use this approach to download documentations for offline reference, since they're mostly static.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most current version of HTTrack supports resumption of broken downloads. This is also built into wget, which is an old Linux tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue I have observed with the latter, however, is that it doesn't seem to get the CSS style files accordingly; therefore, you may have aesthetic issues with it. I have not had this problem with HTTrack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HTTrack is multiplatform supported. There are versions for Android, Windows, and Linux, &lt;a href="http://www.httrack.com/page/2/"&gt;downloadable here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical command for wget is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ wget --continue --wait=20 --limit-rate=20K -r -p -U [BROWSER] [URL_TO_SITE]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ wget --continue --wait=20 --limit-rate=20K -r -p -U Mozilla http://takwas.github.io/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-28:article/save-web-for-offline.html</guid><category>wget</category><category>httrack</category><category>download</category><category>offline</category><category>save</category><category>website</category><category>internet</category><category>planet</category></item><item><title>Wholesome Learning</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/wholesome-learning.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I often tell people that I don't get much free time to watch movies, which is true. Nonetheless, I try to make the most of the few ones I get to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I watch a movie, I make sure to follow it up with some mini-research (mostly on &lt;a href="http://wikipedia.org"&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;) if it presents any interesting new piece of information; be it fact or fiction I learn all the same! Of course, not every movie gives me something to read about, but I try not to miss my after-movie review when I come across the few ones that do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an instance, I have recently watched the "&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Theory_of_Everything_(2014_film)"&gt;The Theory of Everything&lt;/a&gt;" -- one of a number of movies that have been created to document the life of renowned scientist, &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stephen_Hawking"&gt;Stephen Hawking&lt;/a&gt;. That movie revealed a lot more about a man whom, although I have long admired, I had only skimmed the bits of his life and journey. Watching the movie brought me closer to his personality, achievements and also importantly, his &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amyotrophic_lateral_sclerosis"&gt;medical condition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of learning is not your everyday classroom setting or some online tutorial; well, of course we never learn everything from the classroom! However, my point is that these movies -- the good ones -- do not only serve to entertain us, but present us knowledge alongside. Some would call this "edutainment". It is indirect learning, but I can tell you for certain that this is one way I've picked up knowledge of many things I would ordinarily not seek for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's more? Movie production crews are very mindful of their usage of time, so they tend to cramp it all to fit within the conventional 1-2 hour duration of screen time, hiding some details in the process. This is especially evident with movies that are book-based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it's not all movies. There are of course, other sources I learn from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I have not really taking any writing course despite my yearnings for qualitative writing, I have over time continued to gauge the quality of my writings both with the help of some kind reviewers and through self review, I am always glad to hear positive comments; and I make certain to improve on the negative ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But most importantly, I learn and improve -- almost passively -- from simply taking in other people's works. When I scour the net for information or read blog posts or articles, I am not just getting what I need at that moment, but I am also taking in, albeit subconsciously, the presentation style of the document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, one of such rich places, content wise, is &lt;a href="http://quora.com"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;top writers&lt;/em&gt; (people who often give good answers to questions and get frequent &lt;em&gt;upvotes&lt;/em&gt; from other members of the Quora community) are often very articulate and neat in their prose. So somehow, again subconsciously, I have been taking cues from those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, when you chat, try to avoid the use of SMS language. In my opinion, it negatively affects your writing. Sometimes I'd unconsciously use "pls" instead of "please" while writing formally. Also, I use chats as playground for practicing good sentence constructions. So, I don't abbreviate unnecessarily, and I try to use punctuations appropriately. I advise you do same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side note, I find that even though my writing is not exactly top-notch, when I re-read stuff I have written ten days later, I am usually quite impressed and can make improvements. So as a word of advice, "do not despise the days of your little beginnings." Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also take time to listen to talks (especially &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks"&gt;TED talks&lt;/a&gt;) and podcasts. Whether it be commuting time, or time I'm doing some laundry, I try to maximise my use of time; &lt;strong&gt;who says multitasking is a myth&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, in &lt;a href="/i-am-reading-papers"&gt;crowdsourcing for academic paper suggestions&lt;/a&gt;, one of the folks who answered &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-recommended-list-of-essays-papers-to-read-one-per-day-in-2016-for-an-autodidact-who-wants-to-widen-his-horizon?share=1"&gt;my question on Quora&lt;/a&gt; suggested I read transcripts of TED talks. It wouldn't come as a surprise to anyone conversant with these talks that they are so rich and insightful. They bring to you a wide array of perspectives from different minds across the globe. Bottom line is, whether you agree with their postulations or not, you learn!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you'll keep these points in mind as you explore life, you'll find that there are lots of activities that can educate you and give you pleasure at the same time. Try to learn from all of your day-to-day activities and life experiences. So if an activity doesn't &lt;em&gt;somehow&lt;/em&gt; benefit you whilst eating into your time, &lt;em&gt;do your hardest&lt;/em&gt; to abstain from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips for getting better at English usage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;strong&gt;widely&lt;/strong&gt;; cross-genre reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play word games (crosswords, scrabble, ...)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch (and listen to) English speakers &lt;strong&gt;with intent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make the dictionary, thesaurus and any other similar lookup book (e.g. references for idioms, phrasal verbs) your friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in online English communities. An example is the ##English channel on &lt;a href="irc://irc.freenode.net/python"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write consciously, and often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speak English &lt;strong&gt;confidently&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-11:article/wholesome-learning.html</guid><category>learning</category><category>reading</category><category>ted</category><category>podcast</category><category>activity</category><category>movie</category></item><item><title>I am Reading Papers</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/i-am-reading-papers.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If I had a resolution for the new year, it would be my plan to read one academic paper per day. I feel as though reading people's documented research work would help broaden my knowledge and deepen my insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I started looking for a way to crowdsource paper suggestions from a source, namely &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-recommended-list-of-essays-papers-to-read-one-per-day-in-2016-for-an-autodidact-who-wants-to-widen-his-horizon?share=1"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;. However, as I didn't get the much needed feedback in due time, &lt;a href="http://google.com/"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; was my next stop. My google search led me to &lt;a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love"&gt;this page on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After launching the first paper in my document-reader software, I was surprised to see that my earlier projections of papers being under 20 pages was flawed, and so I decided to replan the whole paper-reading thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I will now attempt to read at least one paper per week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this are not far fetched. I don't want to consume these publications like some fictional works. Instead, I want to read to near-full if not full understanding of their content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper I am currently reading, my first, is "Architectural Styles and the Design of Network-based Software Architectures" by &lt;strong&gt;Roy Thomas Fielding&lt;/strong&gt;. It was his submission for a doctoral program in the year 2000.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 05:15:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-11:article/i-am-reading-papers.html</guid><category>essay</category><category>paper</category><category>reading</category><category>dissertation</category><category>activity</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 6: January 6, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-06-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I attended church service early this morning just before returning home from the vigil I attended last night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My sister returned to school today. I had accompanied my aunt to drop her off at the park. On our way back from there, I alighted from the vehicle to pay a quick visit to the market, where I bought a few things before returning home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pondering on the notions of &lt;em&gt;bliss&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;nothingness&lt;/em&gt; today. The concept of "nothingness" was inspired by a "TEDcast"  -- that's &lt;em&gt;TED&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;podcast&lt;/em&gt; :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel I don't attain bliss because of my usual mood combinations: I'm usually either &lt;strong&gt;excited/jovial and loud&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;angry and extremely quiet/taciturn&lt;/strong&gt;. But what I desire as the perfect combo for me is &lt;strong&gt;joy and quietude&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I wish I'd be so happy and quietly, gracefully appreciate the &lt;em&gt;art&lt;/em&gt; of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thought that came up today was that of my outward personality. I grew up thinking my own didn't appreciate me. That the strangers (some of whom have become friends) I was introduced to were the ones who loved me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I realise that I am only clothed when I go out, and people simply adore my neat appearance. Back at my source called home, I am fully naked and the attitude I put up is the real me -- no makeup attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if the people here (at home) have been able to put up with me until now, then I feel I should show some appreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also thought of curating a list of must-learn Python modules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been trying to get acquainted with testing and packaging in Python. So I have been putting some time into learning this.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 23:59:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-10:article/life-log-06-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 5: January 5, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-05-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 5.30AM after failing to properly wake at 2AM, ignoring my alarm earlier. Because of my intention to wake at 2AM, I had refused taking dinner yesterday, and asked that it be reserved until this morning. I guess I just couldn't help the sleepiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I visited IRC yesterday, I enquired about "hacks for reading". The answer I got was a link to a &lt;a href="http://english.glendale.cc.ca.us/speed1.html"&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt;. Visiting that page today, I found these awesome speed reading tips: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pre-scan the material, before actually reading thouroughly. Get an overview of the main points/headings/subheadings beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read with intent. Once you have a grasp of the main ideas, you can read with an inquisitive mindset. Question the main points, and read as if you are searching for answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kill the voice in your head ... and mouth! Avoid vocalization and sub-vocalization; let your brain do the work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read in word clusters (phrases), rather than word after word. This needs some getting used to, as I've seen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid re-reading the same phrases again. Reading should be forward ever, and almost backward never.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand that every material may not be read with the same speed. E.g newspapers can be read pretty fast, whereas technical stuff may not be read so fast, but in detail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surfing the net, I also found some &lt;a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Comb-an-Afro"&gt;hair-combing tips&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mosturize the hair (dampen it with water) before combing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply a generous amount of oil (Olive oil in my case)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comb gently (backwards or forwards), starting from the ends, and repeating until the roots (scalp)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent some time on the road today going from where I live, Bariga, to Ajah, both in Lagos State. I managed to catch some sleep on the road, and also do some reading -- I read a portion of a book I'm currently reading -- &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12232938-the-lovely-bones"&gt;"The Lovely Bones"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended a vigil at the church tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-10:article/life-log-05-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 4: January 4, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-04-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; woke up at exactly 2AM. I think two things I did yesterday made it easy for me to wake up that early: one, I had siesta; and two, I didn't eat dinner. I have noticed you gain more control over your night time sleep when you fail to eat supper. If you must eat however, I would reckon you go with something extremely light; even a beverage should suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon waking up, I checked Facebook, and was thrill-inspired by the status that appeared at the very top. It was by the creator of Facebook himself, Mark Zuckerberg. How inspiring it is to learn that someone of that calibre still gave himself a book reading challenge -- he did so last year -- and on top of that, gave himself a new goal of building an AI for the new year -- he specifically said he'll do the coding himself, not instruct a technical team to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But it's a different kind of rewarding to build things yourself, so this year my personal challenge is to do that."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the next few hours cleaning up some not-yet-published scribbles and blog posts. I tried to code, but ended up just doing a little bit of reading, then returning to sleep at about 5AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up again at about 7AM. I grabbed my breakfast pretty early, and then set off to do some much overdue laundry. That plus some other other cleaning chores took some hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I spent the rest of the day at my aunt's shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There, I spent some time learning about &lt;a href="http://docs.python-guide.org/en/latest/writing/tests/"&gt;how to test code in Python&lt;/a&gt;. I learnt about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://pythontesting.net/framework/unittest/unittest-introduction/"&gt;unit testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://pythontesting.net/framework/doctest-introduction/#example"&gt;doc testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the latter being the easier one in my opinion. I also peeked into the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://twistedmatrix.com/documents/current/api/index.html"&gt;twisted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; networking library which I'll need for coding my IRC bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, I learned that it's good practice to keep "running code" (script) separate from algorithm code and data-handling code.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-07:article/life-log-04-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 3: January 3, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-03-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I didn't read the bible this morning, but the family had a morning devotion as usual. My sleep was a rather short one, spanning about three hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the devotion, I got ready for church service. I got to the church at exactly 9AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't called up to interpret during the service, in fact, no youth was. The interpretion was done by one of the elders, Elder Ogunkomaya. I would think this had to do with the service being the first Sunday service for the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being the first Sunday of the year, one would expect some sort of thanksgiving service. That it was, but only slightly. I guess the full package isn't until the first Sunday in February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two prophecies, and one of them mentioned that, the service need not be rushed. This is worthy of note because, prior to both prophecies, the pastor had asked the prophets to keep their prophecies short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sermon was tagged "Unselfish Desires ...". While I particularly liked this topic, I wasn't very pleased with some of the prayer points that followed. In my opinion, they seemed rather contradictory to the theme of the sermon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, I had a much needed siesta -- something I'm very grateful for. I slept off while listening to a &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/helen_fisher_tells_us_why_we_love_cheat?language=en"&gt;third TED talk&lt;/a&gt; of the afternoon. I really enjoyed &lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_the_paradox_of_choice?language=en"&gt;one of the talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, that talked about "choice". I found the talk interesting because I could easily agree with the speaker's postulations. During his presentation, the speaker, Barry Schwartz said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The secret to happiness -- this is what you all came for -- the secret to happiness is low expectations."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was woken from my sleep afterwards by my pastor's son, Tosin. He had been sent to fetch me. My pastor's wife and children had to travel the following morning, so needed some gas in their car for the trip. For this I drove out to get some petrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just before I could drive out, an incidence caused some delay. His son had carelessly locked the car key in the vehicle; alas, there were no spare keys. So this became the hurdle we had to face for the next 30-45 minutes. What's more: he had ignited the vehicle just before locking it in, so the car was running the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, with the help of a few folks -- good thing to be a &lt;em&gt;good pastor&lt;/em&gt;; lots of folks came around to help very quickly -- we got a metal bar into the door and removed the lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over two hours later, I got the fuel, but not while I drove around searching. I had returned in disappointment and parked the car. In our little gas-haunting adventure, we had failed to obtain that which we sought for owing to general scarcity. In fact, on three occasions, we were told that the fuel in the station's supply was exhausted when it was only a couple of cars to our turn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In eventual frustration, I managed to get the car back home with the little fuel left in it. Afterwards, I left with my gallon in a commercial tricycle headed in a different direction as the one I had previously traveled in. Surprisingly, I met a newly opened petrol station only a minute or two into the journey. They were eagerly distributing the scarce commodity to their new customers; I too joined the party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a different note, my sister returned home from my cousins' a few minutes before I got back home. She came back with a diary and calender for me, which I very much appreciate. What I need to complete that set is a wrist-watch in a bid to be well organised in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] The TED Talks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/barry_schwartz_on_the_paradox_of_choice?language=en"&gt;The paradox of choice&lt;/a&gt; - By Barry Schwartz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/philip_zimbardo_prescribes_a_healthy_take_on_time?language=en"&gt;The psychology of time&lt;/a&gt; - By Philip Zimbardo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/helen_fisher_tells_us_why_we_love_cheat?language=en"&gt;Why we love; why we cheat&lt;/a&gt; - By Helen Fisher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-05:article/life-log-03-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 2: January 2, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-02-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On the night of January 1, the previous night, while writing for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="/category/life-log.html"&gt;Life Log&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I laid on the dinning chairs hoping to wake as soon as power was restored. For whatever reasons, it wasn't until one of my alarms went off at &lt;strong&gt;5.15AM&lt;/strong&gt; that I got up to realize that the power had long been supplied. At the time, my cousin, Deji was watching Sky Sports in the parlour area of the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On waking up I read the bible. This is something I have not been doing consistently, however, this time, I don't intend to rush through this; so I'm taking it very slow and hopefully steady. I read thirteen verses: &lt;strong&gt;Genesis 1.1-13&lt;/strong&gt;. These verses describe the &lt;strong&gt;first three days of Creation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, I reminded myself of my plan to begin reading academic papers today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My aunt and the rest of the family, on waking up, joined us in the living room, and we said our morning prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a Saturday, it was only natural that we would do some sanitation. And so that followed. I did spend 'extra' amount of time cleaning and reassembling my small makeshift wardrobe (testament to my obsessions with cleaning).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At noon, I had my meal, and went on to spend some time on IRC while doing some other regular things I would do usually do on my computer: sort files, check code and repos on &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, read code, surf the web sourcing more and more general knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was on IRC, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;empdokles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (an IRC buddy) asked if we could work together on an application messaging extension for &lt;a href="http://flask.pocoo.org"&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;. I think it's a great idea that would also require quite a bit of a learning curve. For instance, neither of us is good with Javascript, but our intended application would definitely need it, so we'd need to learn that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening, I was able to fix a small bug with my blog that was caused by conflicting options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With regards to time and upcoming events, I under pressure to contribute code to my team's projects, particularly &lt;strong&gt;project &lt;em&gt;jobnownow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the one we intend to get out as soon as possible. I am only trying to be calm and organized, as when the year's activities are fully resumed, &lt;em&gt;time would become a wilder horse to tame&lt;/em&gt;, something, obvious though it seems, I thank my mother for pointing my blinded attention to. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I still have quite a lot of things lined up. Some might be done, and some I may have to let go. Among them, four projects for my team -- one is a hospital information management system application for a client. I also have a pending Java certification examination, the OCAJP 1Z0-803 examination, which was again postponed until mid-January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I have entreprenuerial and Python meetups which I signed up for last year. I also have my eyes -- but not my mind -- on the &lt;a href="http://cchubnigeria.com/blog/"&gt;BBC Africa's ideas workshop&lt;/a&gt; scheduled for later this month at CcHub, Yaba. And very recently, a co-developer acquaintance at NIIT informed me of Facebook's &lt;a href="https://www.internet.org/innovationchallenge"&gt;app innovation challenge&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href="http://internet.org"&gt;Internet.org&lt;/a&gt; for Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's also the &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/lagos/"&gt;DjangoGirls web development workshop&lt;/a&gt; coming up. I signed up for this as a mentor last December after learning about the event via the Python-Nigeria mailing list. This one won't hold until February 2016 though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside these events, I have plans to code my own IRC bot. So I'm making efforts towards that as well. At the moment, I am trying to write unit tests for an open source bot, &lt;a href="http://github.com/takwas/theb0t"&gt;&lt;em&gt;ekan0ra&lt;/em&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;batul&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;. I also started working on my own bot last year: &lt;a href="http://github.com/takwas/sawkat"&gt;sawkat&lt;/a&gt;. I have begun learning about the &lt;a href="https://github.com/twisted/twisted"&gt;&lt;code&gt;twisted&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Python library which is used for coding IRC clients and bots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a different note, I delayed my new year greetings messages until about 10PM. And that's when I unleashed them to their respective recipients. I'm sure the reponses would be flooding in by morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Past 12AM, I got to reading the introductory part of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Roy Fielding's&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; well known dissertation on software architecting, particulary because it is also widely recommended to anyone looking to fully comprehend and build &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer"&gt;RESTful APIs&lt;/a&gt;. Prior to this, I had no idea what the typical size of an academic dissertation was; I had projected something under 20 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my disappointment, I opened Roy's work to behold a close-to-200-page work. As a result of this, I have now rethought my paper reading plan. I will no longer try to complete one paper per day. Instead, I'll spread these papers across days and try to read them through. So help me God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] Apply for the DjangoGirls workshop - &lt;a href="https://djangogirls.org/lagos/apply/"&gt;https://djangogirls.org/lagos/apply/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This event is being discussed on the Python-Nigeria mailing list. Subscribe to this here: &lt;a href="https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria"&gt;https://mail.python.org/mailman/listinfo/python-nigeria&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-03:article/life-log-02-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Life-Log 1: January 1, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/life-log-01-january-2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The year 2016 kicked off on a rather normal note. Last night, a few hours before 12AM, we (me and my aunt's family) were at the church. Church service lasted till just after new year -- about 12.20AM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got home and I broke my day-long food break (no pun intended). I had some malt (Amstel Malta) -- I didn't get one to buy at the time we left church. I would later refuse to take any of the fizzy drinks offered during lunch because of this; plus I felt (for sentimental reasons) that my aunt might not have been pleased I took one of the malt drinks (there were four cans, and I had one of them) in the refrigerator -- and milk (Hollandia Milk, sold for 130 naira). We had prayers, and then it was the next meal round for me. I had some &lt;em&gt;garri&lt;/em&gt; and chicken, which of course, my aunt handed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, getting up at about 6AM, we kick started the day. We were to attend church is the practice at my aunt's church. I have partaken in that, the last two years. So I went on to wash the two cars -- my aunts' and her husbands'. We left the house after 9 O'Clock, and when we arrived at the church, it was already 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first-day-of-the-year program is usually geared towards the announcement of a new &lt;strong&gt;anchor&lt;/strong&gt; -- something we chant in faith, at the end of every church service, all year round. Amongst other things, the anchor's declaration is usually preceded by about three prophecies. And so it was today. The announcement came in the third: &lt;strong&gt;"O God: Thou art my HELP, and my DELIVERER"&lt;/strong&gt;; a declaration drawn out of Psalm 70 vs 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rest of the family, I left the church after 4PM, after having stayed in traffic for about an hour. We had left Folabi and Dapo -- two of my cousins -- at the church. They would much later, much to their surprise, find their way home themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I got a call from my pastor -- Pastor Odusina -- to check up on his phone, and help fix an issue. Alas, the issue was that his newly installed Skype app wasn't connecting to the internet, and was displaying an "offline" status. When, I got there, it just worked without me touching it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently helped purchase a new smartphone for my pastor's wife, and offered to help diagnose her laggy old phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were the activities that took up most of my evening, even until just before now (current system time: 21.54) that I'm writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to hack some code tonight, but there is no power supply at the moment; this battery'll only last a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my plans for 2016, I hope to read a paper a day as a way to become ever more read and deepen my insight in my autodidactic journey. I haven't read any today, but I found some &lt;a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love"&gt;very awesome resource on Github&lt;/a&gt;, a curation of computer science based academic papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am crowdsourcing for paper suggestions. I welcome you to contribute your to-read paper/essay suggestions in the comments. I also have &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-a-recommended-list-of-essays-papers-to-read-one-per-day-in-2016-for-an-autodidact-who-wants-to-widen-his-horizon-but-focus-on-Soft-Engr?share=1"&gt;this question on Quora&lt;/a&gt; where you may also post your answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Quora, I found &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/Obinna-Okechukwu"&gt;this really interesting profile&lt;/a&gt; on Quora minutes after returning from the new year cross-over church service. He has a &lt;a href="https://tcsnotes.quora.com/"&gt;Quora-hosted blog&lt;/a&gt;, where he reviews or puts details of Computer Science papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/James-L-Moyer?share=1"&gt;this other guy&lt;/a&gt; -- creator of &lt;a href="http://www.TheAutodidactLife.com"&gt;AutodidactLife&lt;/a&gt; -- who encouraged me to read transcripts of TED talks. His answers on Quora show that he has some insightful knowledge on autodidactism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More personally, I didn't speak with my mum today -- something I find rather strange for the first day of the year, but I did call my grandma and sister. My sister, Tobi, is with a cousin (Aunt Ladun) for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2016 11:35:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-01:article/life-log-01-january-2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category></item><item><title>Slack is Tweak-friendly</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I migrated the locked default channel on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is a communication platform built for teams. While it is free by default, there are features reserved for paid users. However, the free version already comes with a ton of cool features, and is highly usable as is, especially for teams that are relatively small. My team has stuck with this unpaid version of the application for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we decided to have our clients join our Slack team, with some envisaged benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would ease the process of keeping the client up-to-date on project progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would bring our clients to our preferred communication platform, bringing them all in one place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could leverage some of the many tools available for use with Slack to improve our communication with clients. It's worth noting that Slack is very API friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In doing this, we were presented with a small challenge. All of our previous conversations which had mostly being in the public, general channel, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, were now open to our newly signed-on client. Some of these conversations obviously included stuff we would rather be more privy about. This meant I had to quickly find a way to &lt;em&gt;migrate&lt;/em&gt; -- I chose not to &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; -- the messages in the hope that he had not scrolled back through the channel's message log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have been easier if Slack allowed certain modifications to the default channel named &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For instance, Slack prevents the deletion of this channel. On top of that, Slack puts some restrictions on private channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/213185307-Deleting-a-channel"&gt;deleted, but can be &lt;em&gt;archived&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be changed to &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; channels even though the reverse is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These limitations notwithstanding, the following explains my approach to tackling the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I used Slack's &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201658943-Exporting-your-team-s-Slack-history"&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; feature to backup all of our conversations, including channel information. A caveat here is, &lt;em&gt;Slack does not include private channels' data with exported data by default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but thankfully, we hadn't any private rooms at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Slack exports team data in JSON format, making it very easy to work with. Having downloaded the exported data, I started looking through it for parts that I could tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some top-level (&lt;strong&gt;root folder&lt;/strong&gt;) files which included meta-data about users, teams and channels. Then there were also folders for each channel, in which, conversation logs were kept, grouped by days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I edited the &lt;code&gt;channels.json&lt;/code&gt; file in the top-level directory, and changed the name of the channel &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;, which contained the messages, to some new name. Then I went and renamed the folder named &lt;code&gt;general&lt;/code&gt;, to this new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these changes in place, I compressed the modified files alongside the unmodified ones into a &lt;em&gt;zip&lt;/em&gt; archive; the original Slack-exported data had come in a zip file as well. Slack allows you to &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201748703-Importing-message-history"&gt;import&lt;/a&gt; this zip file into your Slack team, which was what I did next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the import, Slack automatically tried to match detected channels (from the import) with existing ones, after-which I was presented with a page that displayed the mapping suggestions. I simply set it not to map but create new channels instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful completion of the imports, I went on to delete all the messages in the existing &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt; channel. Those messages were now the contents of a newly minted channel, created using the new name I previously gave to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these in place, I did two more things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I edited and marked the new channel as &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I welcomed our new client to our Slack space &lt;strong&gt;;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] More on Slack's default channel - #general&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] Exporting private data from Slack&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 23:23:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-25:article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html</guid><category>slack</category><category>configuration</category><category>json</category><category>general</category><category>backup</category><category>communication</category><category>planet</category></item><item><title>To be Forearmed is to be Help-ready</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/readying-for-net-help.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I felt compelled to write this after my personal experience trying to get help with my code on IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love to make the computer do things exactly the way we want, so some of us choose to take the bold step of learning to communicate with the machine. And it is not uncommon to find many of our burgeoning kind go from &lt;em&gt;location to location on the web space&lt;/em&gt; trying to get help along the way. We are prompt to ask questions when we sight help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you learn to program, you are often encouraged to &lt;strong&gt;learn by doing.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain of computer programming or software development is a very practical one. Before now, I had carried this very principle everywhere with me -- in fact, preached it -- but hadn't really put it to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about learning languages (or technologies) by reading big manuals is that, often times, beginners will approach the process like they would any other literature book. But that is clearly a wrong approach as empirical evidence has shown. You don't read these things to simply stomach them. Instead, you swallow and then post-process. In essence, you ruminate over stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, the only way you can really process what you read is to &lt;strong&gt;try things out and see results for yourself&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeks ago, while building an app, I visited IRC frequently to ask questions on just about everything that was unclear to me. While this mode of communication and seeking help is encouraged, abuse of it is strongly discouraged. The good guys over on the IRC channels get pissed off when it appears you're boycotting available resources like documentation, preferring to be spoonfed the whole time. (Remember this is not &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, where the philosophy is for you to ask more and more questions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the sort of thing that happened to me when I began &lt;em&gt;flooding&lt;/em&gt; the channels with my persistent querying. Most of the time the IRC folks kept pointing me to the documentation, as workarounds for most of the issues I had were already documented. A lot of things became much clearer when I decided to finally &lt;a href="https://readthedocs.org/"&gt;read-the-docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I learn from that? &lt;strong&gt;"Do your own research!"&lt;/strong&gt; It's so easy to skip this part, but if you make efforts at finding things out for yourself, you'll be surprised at how much you can dig out without having to bug people. However, this does not guarantee that even the few important questions you'll ask may not be met with hostility, but do not let that discourage you. The people who appear to be unwelcoming are doing so only as a way to discourage you from being over-dependent on the channel.
Another advantage of finding things for yourself is that, you learn the &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and not just the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's fair to quote &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/about/"&gt;Armin Ronacher&lt;/a&gt; here,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"And it's not just asking questions; questioning other people, like what other people do or what you do yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, the worst parts in all of my libraries are where I took the design from somewhere else. And it's not because I know better, it's because pretty much everything everybody does at any point in time has some sort of design decision behind it ... that major decision process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So someone came up with a solution for a particular problem, and he thought about it and then wrote it down. But if you look at someone else's design, you might no longer understand why the decision was made in the first place. And ... in fact, if the original implementation is ten years old, who knows if the design ideas behind it are still entirely correct."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Personally, I like to answer questions and help put people on track. Nonetheless, if the queries got too overwhelming -- especially coming from the same person -- I would eventually lose interest in answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let me remind you of some &lt;strong&gt;tidbits or etiquettes of IRC&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construct your questions well (concise, well written and straight-to-the-point questions are more likely to attract help)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't EVER post code in a channel! &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pastebin"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it and share the link in the channel instead. While at it, don't post your entire code (unless you specifically need to). Post only the relevant portion -- the one you have an issue with. The only exception to this is if the snippet of code is considerably short, say one or two lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be overly respectful. Yes, dont be too respectful -- &lt;em&gt;cut all the 'Sirs'&lt;/em&gt;. Only be moderately polite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure you have and use a registered nick. This gives you an identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last one is entirely my opinion but it's also based on what I have observed. &lt;strong&gt;Don't just be a leech, try to contribute to the community&lt;/strong&gt;. Answer questions when you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do you look to before looking to IRC? There are three sources you may &lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt; from before turning to internet-relay-chat for help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. * Documentation is the manual the creator or experts of a software product or tool provide their users with. So you want to know the ins and outs of a technology? That's the right place to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read blog posts&lt;/strong&gt; related to your topic-area. Blog posts are often based on people's experiences, so you're likely to find help from there, especially if the writer has faced the same issue. Remember to &lt;code&gt;bookmark&lt;/code&gt; the really helpful ones as you go ;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last and very important. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/learn-to-read-the-source-luke/"&gt;Read the source code!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This is two-fold: First is actually looking into your own code carefully and seeing what syntax or semantic errors you might have made. Secondly, you look into the original code of libraries/frameworks you are using if they are open source, otherwise revert to documentation. With this, you have it all stripped to its bare bones. Point blank! The source code reveals everything you need to know, once you know how to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So why not arm yourself properly before going to post that question. That way, you would not only make it easier to get help [for yourself], but you would be better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] Some Pastebin platforms I use:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastebin.com"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.ubuntu.com"&gt;Ubuntu Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastie.org"&gt;Pastie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.pound-python.org"&gt;Spacepaste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.linux.chat"&gt;##Linux on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; provides a platform which supports version-controlled pastes: &lt;a href="http://gist.github/com"&gt;Github Gists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Because &lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt; heavily depends on Javascript, some people have complained of text-rendering issues possibly arising from browser-compatibility issues with it. So take caution using it. That said, I love its ease-of-use. It supports the use of keyboard shortcuts such as &lt;code&gt;[Ctrl]+[S]&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 12:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-15:article/readying-for-net-help.html</guid><category>irc</category><category>help</category><category>programming</category><category>beginner</category><category>pastebin</category><category>documentation</category><category>practice</category><category>dev</category><category>planet</category></item></channel></rss>