<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>acetakwas.log();</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/</link><description>while True: print    &lt;strong&gt;\&lt;/strong&gt;</description><atom:link href="http://takwas.github.io/feeds/tosin-damilare-james-animashaun.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 07:20:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Life-Log: January 1, 2016</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/01.01.2016.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;01.01.2016&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The year 2016 kicked off on a rather normal note. Last night, a few hours before 12AM, we (me and my aunt's family) were at the church. Church service lasted till just after new year -- about 12.20AM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got home and I broke my day-long food break (no pun intended). I had some malt (Amstel Malta) -- I didn't get one to buy at the time we left church. I would later refuse to take any of the fizzy drinks offered during lunch because of this; plus I felt my aunt might not have been pleased I took one of the malt drinks (there were four cans, and I had one of them) in the refrigerator -- and milk (Hollandia Milk, sold for 130 naira). We had prayers, and then it was the next meal round for me. I had some &lt;em&gt;garri&lt;/em&gt; and chicken, which of course, my aunt handed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, getting up at about 6AM, we kick started the day. We were to attend church is the practice at my aunt's church. I have partaken in that, the last two years. So I went on to wash the two cars -- my aunts' and her husbands'. We left the house after 9 O'Clock, and when we arrived at the church, it was already 10AM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first-day-of-the-year program is usually geared towards the announcement of a new &lt;strong&gt;anchor&lt;/strong&gt; -- something we chant in faith, at the end of every church service, all year round. Amongst other things, the anchor's declaration is usually preceded by about three prophecies. And so it was today. The announcement came in the third: &lt;strong&gt;"O God: Thou art my HELP, and my DELIVERER"&lt;/strong&gt;; a declaration drawn out of Psalm 70 vs 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rest of the family, I left the church after 4PM, after having stayed in traffic for about an hour. We had left Folabi and Dapo -- two of my cousins -- at the church. They would much later, much to their surprise, find their way home themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At home, I got a call from my pastor to check up on his phone, and help fix an issue. Alas, the issue was that his newly installed Skype app wasn't connecting to the internet, and was displaying an "offline" status. When, I got there, it just worked without me touching it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next was his wife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently helped purchase a new smartphone for my pastor's wife, and offered to help diagnose her laggy old phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were the activities that took up most of my evening, even until just before now (current system time: 21.54) that I'm writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am hoping to hack some code tonight, but there is no power supply at the moment; this battery'll only last a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of my plans for 2016, I hope to read a paper a day as a way to become ever more read and deepen my insight in my autodidactic journey. I haven't read any today, but I found some &lt;a href="https://github.com/papers-we-love/papers-we-love"&gt;very awesome resource on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am crowdsourcing for paper suggestions. You can contribute your to-read paper/essay suggestions in the comments. I also have this question on Quora: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Quora, I found &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/Obinna-Okechukwu"&gt;this really interesting profile&lt;/a&gt; on Quora minutes after returning from the new year cross-over church service. He has a &lt;a href="https://tcsnotes.quora.com/"&gt;Quora-hosted blog&lt;/a&gt;, where he reviews or puts details of Computer Science papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there was &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/profile/James-L-Moyer?share=1"&gt;this other guy&lt;/a&gt; -- creator of &lt;a href="http://www.TheAutodidactLife.com"&gt;AutodidactLife&lt;/a&gt; -- who encouraged me to read transcripts of TED talks. His answers on Quora show that he has some insightful knowledge on autodidactism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More personally, I didn't speak with my mum today, but I did call my grandma and sister. My sister is with a cousin (Aunt Ladun) for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 07:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2016-01-01:article/01.01.2016.html</guid><category>life</category><category>journal</category><category>diary</category><category>january</category><category>first day</category><category>church</category><category>fast</category><category>family</category></item><item><title>Slack is Tweak-friendly</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html</link><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I migrated the locked default channel on Slack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://slack.com"&gt;Slack&lt;/a&gt; is a communication platform built for teams. While it is free by default, there are features reserved for paid users. However, the free version already comes with a ton of cool features, and is highly usable as is, especially for teams that are relatively small. My team has stuck with this unpaid version of the application for a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, we decided to have our clients join our Slack team, with some envisaged benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would ease the process of keeping the client up-to-date on project progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would bring our clients to our preferred communication platform, bringing them all in one place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could leverage some of the many tools available for use with Slack to improve our communication with clients. It's worth noting that Slack is very API friendly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
In doing this, we were presented with a small challenge. All of our previous conversations which had mostly being in the public, general channel, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, were now open to our newly signed-on client. Some of these conversations obviously included stuff we would rather be more privy about. This meant I had to quickly find a way to &lt;em&gt;migrate&lt;/em&gt; -- I chose not to &lt;em&gt;delete&lt;/em&gt; -- the messages in the hope that he had not scrolled back through the channel's message log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This would have been easier if Slack allowed certain modifications to the default channel named &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For instance, Slack prevents the deletion of this channel. On top of that, Slack puts some restrictions on private channels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/213185307-Deleting-a-channel"&gt;deleted, but can be &lt;em&gt;archived&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can't be changed to &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; channels even though the reverse is possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
These limitations notwithstanding, the following explains my approach to tackling the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I used Slack's &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201658943-Exporting-your-team-s-Slack-history"&gt;export&lt;/a&gt; feature to backup all of our conversations, including channel information. A caveat here is, &lt;em&gt;Slack does not include private channels' data with exported data by default&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[2]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but thankfully, we hadn't any private rooms at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, Slack exports team data in JSON format, making it very easy to work with. Having downloaded the exported data, I started looking through it for parts that I could tweak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were some top-level (&lt;strong&gt;root folder&lt;/strong&gt;) files which included meta-data about users, teams and channels. Then there were also folders for each channel, in which, conversation logs were kept, grouped by days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I edited the &lt;code&gt;channels.json&lt;/code&gt; file in the top-level directory, and changed the name of the channel &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt;, which contained the messages, to some new name. Then I went and renamed the folder named &lt;code&gt;general&lt;/code&gt;, to this new name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these changes in place, I compressed the modified files alongside the unmodified ones into a &lt;em&gt;zip&lt;/em&gt; archive; the original Slack-exported data had come in a zip file as well. Slack allows you to &lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201748703-Importing-message-history"&gt;import&lt;/a&gt; this zip file into your Slack team, which was what I did next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the import, Slack automatically tried to match detected channels (from the import) with existing ones, after-which I was presented with a page that displayed the mapping suggestions. I simply set it not to map but create new channels instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon successful completion of the imports, I went on to delete all the messages in the existing &lt;em&gt;#general&lt;/em&gt; channel. Those messages were now the contents of a newly minted channel, created using the new name I previously gave to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all these in place, I did two more things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I edited and marked the new channel as &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I welcomed our new client to our Slack space &lt;strong&gt;;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] More on Slack's default channel - #general&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201827866-Renaming-the-general-channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/201898998-Setting-default-channels-for-new-users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[2] Exporting private data from Slack&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports"&gt;https://get.slack.help/hc/en-us/articles/204897248-Understanding-Slack-data-exports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 23:23:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-25:article/migrating-slack-channel-general.html</guid><category>slack</category><category>configuration</category><category>json</category><category>general</category><category>backup</category><category>communication</category><category>planet</category></item><item><title>To be Forearmed is to be Help-ready</title><link>http://takwas.github.io/article/readying-for-net-help.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I felt compelled to write this after my personal experience trying to get help with my code on IRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all love to make the computer do things exactly the way we want, so some of us choose to take the bold step of learning to communicate with the machine. And it is not uncommon to find many of our burgeoning kind go from &lt;em&gt;location to location on the web space&lt;/em&gt; trying to get help along the way. We are prompt to ask questions when we sight help.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you learn to program, you are often encouraged to &lt;strong&gt;learn by doing.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The domain of computer programming or software development is a very practical one. Before now, I had carried this very principle everywhere with me -- in fact, preached it -- but hadn't really put it to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about learning languages (or technologies) by reading big manuals is that, often times, beginners will approach the process like they would any other literature book. But that is clearly a wrong approach as empirical evidence has shown. You don't read these things to simply stomach them. Instead, you swallow and then post-process. In essence, you ruminate over stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In truth, the only way you can really process what you read is to &lt;strong&gt;try things out and see results for yourself&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weeks ago, while building an app, I visited IRC frequently to ask questions on just about everything that was unclear to me. While this mode of communication and seeking help is encouraged, abuse of it is strongly discouraged. The good guys over on the IRC channels get pissed off when it appears you're boycotting available resources like documentation, preferring to be spoonfed the whole time. (Remember this is not &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com"&gt;Quora&lt;/a&gt;, where the philosophy is for you to ask more and more questions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the sort of thing that happened to me when I began &lt;em&gt;flooding&lt;/em&gt; the channels with my persistent querying. Most of the time the IRC folks kept pointing me to the documentation, as workarounds for most of the issues I had were already documented. A lot of things became much clearer when I decided to finally &lt;a href="https://readthedocs.org/"&gt;read-the-docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I learn from that? &lt;strong&gt;"Do your own research!"&lt;/strong&gt; It's so easy to skip this part, but if you make efforts at finding things out for yourself, you'll be surprised at how much you can dig out without having to bug people. However, this does not guarantee that even the few important questions you'll ask may not be met with hostility, but do not let that discourage you. The people who appear to be unwelcoming are doing so only as a way to discourage you from being over-dependent on the channel.
Another advantage of finding things for yourself is that, you learn the &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; and not just the &lt;strong&gt;how&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it's fair to quote &lt;a href="http://lucumr.pocoo.org/about/"&gt;Armin Ronacher&lt;/a&gt; here,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"And it's not just asking questions; questioning other people, like what other people do or what you do yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By far, the worst parts in all of my libraries are where I took the design from somewhere else. And it's not because I know better, it's because pretty much everything everybody does at any point in time has some sort of design decision behind it ... that major decision process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So someone came up with a solution for a particular problem, and he thought about it and then wrote it down. But if you look at someone else's design, you might no longer understand why the decision was made in the first place. And ... in fact, if the original implementation is ten years old, who knows if the design ideas behind it are still entirely correct."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Personally, I like to answer questions and help put people on track. Nonetheless, if the queries got too overwhelming -- especially coming from the same person -- I would eventually lose interest in answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Let me remind you of some &lt;strong&gt;tidbits or etiquettes of IRC&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construct your questions well (concise, well written and straight-to-the-point questions are more likely to attract help)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't EVER post code in a channel! &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pastebin"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[1]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; it and share the link in the channel instead. While at it, don't post your entire code (unless you specifically need to). Post only the relevant portion -- the one you have an issue with. The only exception to this is if the snippet of code is considerably short, say one or two lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't be overly respectful. Yes, dont be too respectful -- &lt;em&gt;cut all the 'Sirs'&lt;/em&gt;. Only be moderately polite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure you have and use a registered nick. This gives you an identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last one is entirely my opinion but it's also based on what I have observed. &lt;strong&gt;Don't just be a leech, try to contribute to the community&lt;/strong&gt;. Answer questions when you can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do you look to before looking to IRC? There are three sources you may &lt;strong&gt;read&lt;/strong&gt; from before turning to internet-relay-chat for help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read the documentation&lt;/strong&gt;. * Documentation is the manual the creator or experts of a software product or tool provide their users with. So you want to know the ins and outs of a technology? That's the right place to look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read blog posts&lt;/strong&gt; related to your topic-area. Blog posts are often based on people's experiences, so you're likely to find help from there, especially if the writer has faced the same issue. Remember to &lt;code&gt;bookmark&lt;/code&gt; the really helpful ones as you go ;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last and very important. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/learn-to-read-the-source-luke/"&gt;Read the source code!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. This is two-fold: First is actually looking into your own code carefully and seeing what syntax or semantic errors you might have made. Secondly, you look into the original code of libraries/frameworks you are using if they are open source, otherwise revert to documentation. With this, you have it all stripped to its bare bones. Point blank! The source code reveals everything you need to know, once you know how to read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
So why not arm yourself properly before going to post that question. That way, you would not only make it easier to get help [for yourself], but you would be better informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;[1] Some Pastebin platforms I use:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastebin.com"&gt;Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.ubuntu.com"&gt;Ubuntu Pastebin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pastie.org"&gt;Pastie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.pound-python.org"&gt;Spacepaste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://paste.linux.chat"&gt;##Linux on Freenode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href="http://github.com"&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; provides a platform which supports version-controlled pastes: &lt;a href="http://gist.github/com"&gt;Github Gists&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Because &lt;a href="http://hastebin.com"&gt;Hastebin&lt;/a&gt; heavily depends on Javascript, some people have complained of text-rendering issues possibly arising from browser-compatibility issues with it. So take caution using it. That said, I love its ease-of-use. It supports the use of keyboard shortcuts such as &lt;code&gt;[Ctrl]+[S]&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Tosin Damilare James Animashaun</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 12:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>tag:takwas.github.io,2015-12-15:article/readying-for-net-help.html</guid><category>irc</category><category>help</category><category>programming</category><category>beginner</category><category>pastebin</category><category>documentation</category><category>practice</category><category>dev</category><category>planet</category></item></channel></rss>